原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     蜘蛛草   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译     盐湖拔丝凉开水   小酸奶!
校对     小虫草
时间轴     想念Gallifrey的wholock
后期     8T
总监     somehacker  草草
八年后
彼得·帕克电影
两个月后
哈皮  就是问问
我下午2:45放学
可以进行下次任务了
是彼得哦
帕克
哈皮
蛛网液
返校节
学术竞赛
10月13至15日
华盛顿特区
这是你的自行车吗  如果不是  别偷走  蜘蛛侠
美国队长健身挑战
第一关  仰卧起坐
内德
学术竞赛  华盛顿特区
华盛顿  126英里
哈皮
美国学术竞赛
请勿打扰
读取数据集
美国学术竞赛
呼叫  内德
呼叫失败
美国学术竞赛
我是谁
蛛网液
纽约之旅幸存者
返校节
温莎领结
找到会飞秃鹫男一个
蜘蛛侠
飞机的事抱歉了
未知号码  去厕所
奥迪人工智能启动  可以脱手
物归原主  托·斯
蜘蛛侠
英雄归来
蜘蛛侠将回归
这世界要变样了
Things are never gonna be the same now.
看啊
I mean, look at this.
画了外星人
You got aliens.
还有绿色的大块头把楼砸坏
You got big green guys tearing down buildings.
我小时候  画的都是牛仔和印第安人
When I was a kid, I used to draw cowboys and Indians.
其实  得叫美国土著  无所谓了
Actually, it's native American, but whatever.
嗯  不过  告诉你
Yeah. Tell you what, though.
还不赖  是吧
It ain't bad, is it?
是啊  嗯
No. Yeah.
这孩子有前途
Kid's got a future.
是啊
Yeah, well,
走着瞧吧
we'll see, I guess.
不行
No, hey!
那玩意锯不断的
You can't saw through that stuff.
这些外星玩意很结实
These alien bastards are tough.
你得用他们的东西对付他们
You gotta use the stuff they use.
瞧
See?
-好  -好
- All right. - All right.
真高兴你能来啊  下午好
Glad you could join us. Afternoon.
嗯  我的闹钟没响
Yeah. My alarm didn't go off.
是啊  你的闹钟
Yeah, your alarm.
照我说的把那个装甲板摞起来
Look, just go stack that armor plating like I asked you.
这可是个大单
This is a huge deal for us.
请注意
Attention, please!
依照行政命令396b
In accordance with executive order 396b,
所有战后清理工作
all post-battle cleanup operations
均由我们接管
are now under our jurisdiction.
感谢你们的服务  我们会接手了
Thank you for your service. We'll take it from here.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
有资质人员
Qualified personnel.
听着  我跟市政府签了合同
Look, I have a city contract
清理废墟
to salvage all this, okay, with the city, so--
很抱歉  图姆斯先生
I apologize, Mr. Toomes,
但一切清理行动现在都由我们负责了
but all salvage operations are now under our jurisdiction.
请交出全部你们已收集的外星物质
Please turn over any and all exotic materials that you've collected
否则你们将被起诉
or you will be prosecuted.
女士  什么...
Ma'am, what am--?
拜托  过来  女士  拜托
Please. Come here. Hey, lady, come on.
听着
Look...
我为这单活儿买了卡车
I bought trucks for this job.
我还招了新人
I brought in a whole new crew.
这些人都有家室  我也有
These guys have a family. I have a family.
我赌上了一切  我可能丢掉房子的
I'm all in on this. I could lose my house.
抱歉  先生  我也没办法
I'm sorry, sir. There's nothing I can do.
或许下次  别不自量力
Maybe next time, don't overextend yourself.
你说什么
What'd you say?
嗯
Yeah.
他是对的  我不自量力了
He's right. I overextended myself.
别
Don't do it.
都放下
Put 'em down.
如果你有不满
If you have a grievance,
可以去找我的上级
you may take it up with my superiors.
你的上级  那是谁
Your superiors. Who the hell are they?
斯塔克工业和联邦政府的合营企业
A joint venture between Stark Industries and the federal government,
损害控制局
the Department of Damage Control,
将监督外星和其他外来物质的
will oversee the collection and storage of alien
收集和存储
and other exotic materials.
那个搞出烂摊子的混蛋现在又要收钱收拾残局
Now the assholes who made this mess are paid to clean it up.
是啊  都是内部交易
Yeah, it's all rigged.
据专家估计  整个三州地区散落了超过
Experts estimate there are over 1500 tons of exotic material
1500吨的外来物质
scattered throughout the tri-state area.
老大
Hey, chief!
我们还有一车昨天的货
We still have another load from yesterday.
我们得上交的  是吧
We're supposed to turn this in, right?
-我可不去送  -太可惜了
- I ain't hauling it. - It's too bad.
我们可以用那些外星玩意做不少好玩的
We could have made some cool stuff from all that alien junk.
这样吧
I tell you what.
我们不交了
Let's keep it.
这世界在变
The world's changing.
我们也该变变了
It's time we change too.
给  梅森
There you go, Mason.
太棒了
Yeah!
生意很好
Business is good.
纽约市  皇后区
New York. Queens.
这一带不太平  但终归是家
It's a rough borough, but, hey, it's home.
你在跟谁说话
Who you talking to?
没谁  我在拍摄行程
No one. Just making a little video of the trip.
-你不能拿给任何人看  -我知道
- You can't show it to anyone. - Yeah, I know.
那你还变声念旁白
Then why are you narrating in that voice?
-好玩嘛  -好玩
- Because it's fun. - Fun.
你为什么叫哈皮
So why do they call you Happy?
快点  我可不给你拿包  快走
Come on. I'm not carrying your bags. Let's go.
我要先上个厕所吗
Should I go to the bathroom before?
上面有厕所
There's a bathroom on it.
无人驾驶吗  太赞了
No pilot? That's awesome.
-你就坐那儿吗  -嗯
- Is that where you're gonna sit? - Yeah.
你第一次做专机吗
This is your first time on a private plane?
我第一次坐飞机
My first time on any plane.
那个...它...这噪音没问题吗
Should it--? Should it be--? Should it be making that noise?
并没人跟我说过
No one has actually told me
我为什么要来柏林或是我要做什么
why I'm in Berlin or what I'm doing.
好像是美国队长发疯了
Something about Captain America going crazy.
-你到了  -我们住隔壁吗
- This is you. - Oh, we're neighbors?
我们不住同间  换衣服
We're not roommates. Suit up.
好吧  彼得  你行的
Okay, Peter, you got this.
你穿的啥玩意
What the hell are you wearing?
我的战衣啊
It's my suit.
-箱子呢  -什么箱子
- Where's the case? - What case?
那不是我的...什么  我以为那是个橱柜
That's not my... What? I thought that was a closet.
-这里也是我的房间吗  -快去吧
- This is still my room? - Go. Please.
-我的房间好大...  -快去
- My room is way bigger than-- - There.
我找到箱子了  我找到箱子了
I found the case. I found the case. I found the case.
"稍作升级"
"A minor upgrade"?
天呐
Oh, my god.
-穿上  -什么
- Put it on. - What the--?
这是我见过的最酷的东西
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen--
-快点  -我不明白
- Let's go. - But I don't understand.
这是给我的吗  哈皮  哈皮  等等
Is it for me? Happy. Happy, wait.
这太疯狂了  太疯狂了
This is insane. Insane.
看这个啊  看看这眼睛
Look at this thing. Look. Look at the eyes.
-这是我人生最棒的一天  -快点换吧
- The greatest day of my life. - Let's go. Come on.
好了  那是美国队长  钢铁侠  黑寡妇
Okay, there's Captain America, Iron Man, Black Widow.
-那个新来的是谁  -内衣宝宝
- Who's that new guy? - Underoos!
叫我呢  我得走了
Oh, that's me. I gotta go. I gotta go.
大家好
Hey, everyone.
好吧  刚刚太疯狂了
Okay, so the craziest thing just happened.
我跟美国队长打了一架
I just had a fight with Captain America.
我偷了他的盾  还拿盾丢他
I stole his shield. I threw it at him--
搞什么  他变大了  我得走了  等等
What the hell? He's big now. I gotta go. Hang on.
简直太赞了
It was the most amazing thing that ever happened!
斯塔克先生喊  "内衣宝宝"
Mr. Stark was like, "Hey, underoos!"
我就一个翻身偷了美队的盾
I flipped in and stole Cap's shield.
我还说  "大家好啊"
I was like, "What's up, everybody?"
然后  等一下
And then-- hey, just a second!
来了
Coming!
墙不太隔音
We have thin walls here.
你干什么呢  做视频日志吗
What are you doing, a little video diary?
-是啊  -没事
- Yeah. - It's all right.
-换了我也会的  -我叫他别了
- I'd do the same thing. - I told him not to.
他什么都拍  我会抹掉芯片的
He was filming everything. I'm gonna wipe the chip.
知道吗  我们反正也该拍段视频
You know what? We should make an alibi video
当托辞骗你婶婶  准备好了吗
for your aunt anyway. You ready?
-托辞  -拍了吗
- An alibi? - We rolling?
-好啊  -到镜头里来
- Sure. - Get in the frame.
好了
Okay.
梅  你好吗
Hey, May. How you doing?
你穿着什么呢  希望是布料少的
What are you wearing? Something skimpy, I hope.
彼得  这么说不太好
Peter, that's inappropriate.
重来吧  你可以剪辑一下
Let's start over. You can edit it.
三  二  一  你好啊  梅
Three, two, one. Hey, may.
天呐  我想告诉你
My gosh, I wanted to tell you
你侄子这周末在斯塔克实习基地
what an incredible job your nephew did this weekend
表现得太出色了
at the Stark internship retreat.
大家都交口称赞
Everyone was impressed.
拜托
Come on!
并道啊  抱歉
It's a freaking merge. Sorry.
谁叫你不走皇后大道
Because you're not on Queens Boulevard.
哈皮本希望
See, Happy is hoping
能升职到资产管理部
to get bumped up to asset management.
他本是安保主管  再之前是个司机
He was forehead of security, before that he was a driver.
那是私人谈话
That was a private conversation.
我不喜欢拿这事开玩笑  很难启齿的
I don't like joking about this. It was hard to talk about that.
说真的  他是不是拼命打呼噜来着
No, seriously, was he snoring a bunch?
我们到了  到家了
Here we are. End of the line.
哈皮  能让我们单独待会儿吗
Happy, can you give us a moment?
你要我下车吗
You want me to leave the car?
你去把彼得的箱子从后备箱拿出来吧
Why don't you grab Peter's case out of the trunk.
我能留下战衣吗
I can keep the suit?
是的  我们刚刚不正说呢嘛
Yes, we were just talking about it.
但是  帮个忙
Do me a favor, though.
哈皮算是你的负责人
Happy's kind of your point guy on this.
别给他太多压力  别干蠢事
Don't stress him out. Don't do anything stupid.
我看过他的心电图
I've seen his cardiogram.
-好吗  -好
- All right? - Yes.
别做我会做的事
Don't do anything I would do,
更不要做我不会做的事
and definitely don't do anything I wouldn't do.
这之间有一小块灰色区域  就是你的活动范围
There's a little gray area in there. And that's where you operate.
那么我是个复仇者了吗
Wait, does that mean I'm an avenger?
不是
No.
-这个吗  -七楼
- This it? - Seventh floor.
我拿上去吧  不劳您了
I can take that up. You don't have to take it.
-你自己拿啊  -嗯  我自己拿吧
- You're gonna take it? - Yeah, I can take that.
谢谢
Thank you.
那我们下次什么时候...
So when's our next--?
再什么时候去"实习"
When's our next "retreat," you know?
下次任务吗
What, next mission?
对  任务  今后的任务
Yeah, the mission. The missions.
-我们会联络你的  -你有我的号码吗
- We'll call you. - Do you have my numbers?
不  就是会通知你的
No, I mean, we'll call you.
就是有人会打给你的  好吗
Like, someone will call you. All right?
-你团队的人  -那好
- From your team. - Okay. All right.
不是抱你  我就是替你开车门
That's not a hug. I'm just grabbing the door for you.
我们还没那么好呢
We're not there yet.
再见
Bye.
他们会联络我的
They're gonna call me.
你好啊  软蛋·帕克
What's up, Penis Parker?
早上好  中城区科技高中
Rise and shine, Midtown Science and Technology.
学生们  别忘记返校节门票
Students, don't forget about your homecoming tickets.
你返校节有男伴吗
Do you have a date for homecoming?
谢谢  杰森  但我有男伴了
Thanks, Jason, but I already have a date.
-好吧  -嗯
- Okay. - Yeah.
-该死  -你  马上去我办公室
- Damn it. - You, in my office right now.
加入我  我们一起
Join me, and together
建造我的新乐高死星
we'll build my new Llego Death Star.
-什么  -太没劲了
- What? - So lame.
不会吧  太棒了  多少块的
No way. That's awesome. How many pieces?
Three thousand eight hundred and three.
-不可思议  -是啊
- That's insane. - I know.
你想今晚做吗
You want to build it tonight?
今晚不行  我得去斯塔克...
No, I can't tonight. I've got the Stark--
-斯塔克实习  -是啊
- Stark internship. - Yeah, exactly.
总得去做实习
Always got that internship.
是啊  希望
Yeah, well, hopefully,
很快就真能在那儿谋个职了
soon it'll lead to a real job with them.
-那就太棒了  -是吧
- That would be so sweet. - Right?
他会说  "表格做得真好  彼得
He'd be all, "Good job on those spreadsheets, Peter.
给你枚金币"
Here's a gold coin."
我根本不懂工作是什么样的
I don't know how jobs work.
就是这样的
That's exactly how they work.
我会在我家把死星的大体结构搭好
I'll knock out the basic bones of the Death Star at my place.
然后再去你家
I'll come by afterwards.
主要的难点是底座
For the most part, the difficult thing is the base of it.
上部至多两小时就能做好
The top half we can knock out in two hours, tops.
那好啊
That'd be great.
好了  我们如何计算
Okay, so how do we calculate
A点和B点之间的线性加速度
linear acceleration between points a and b?
弗拉士
Flash.
角正弦
It's the product of sine of the angle
乘重力除质量
and gravity divided by the mass.
不对  彼得
Nope. Peter.
还在听吗
You still with us?
在听  在听
Yeah, yeah.
质量抵消了  就是重力乘正弦
Mass cancels out, so it's just gravity times sine.
对  瞧  弗拉士  如果答错
Right. See, Flash, being the fastest
最快也未必是最好的
isn't always the best if you are wrong.
你死定了
You're dead.
今天我们要讨论丹麦物理学家尼尔斯·玻尔
Today we're talking about Danish physicist Niels Bohr,
但相信我  他发现的
but trust me, there's nothing bohr-ing
量子理论  可绝对不无聊
about his discoveries regarding quantum theory.
-丽兹换新上衣了吗  -没有
- Did Liz get a new top? - No.
这件我们见过  只是没配过这条裙子
We've seen that before, but never with that skirt.
丽兹
Liz, hey.
真不错
That looks so good.
我们还是别再盯着看了  否则要像变态了
We should probably stop staring before it gets creepy, though.
已经变态了  你俩真可悲
Too late. You guys are losers.
那为什么跟我们坐一起
Well, then why do you sit with us?
因为我没有朋友
Because I don't have any friends.
下一问题
Let's move to the next question.
最重的自然元素是什么
What is the heaviest naturally-occurring element?
氢是最轻的
Hydrogen's the lightest.
但那不是问题  好吧
That's not the question. Okay. Yeah.
铀
Uranium.
正确  谢谢  亚伯拉罕
That is correct. Thank you, Abraham.
-好啊  -请将书打开到第10页
- Yes. - Open your books to page 10.
彼得  这是全国赛
Peter, it's nationals.
你就不能放一个周末的假吗
Is there no way you could take one weekend off?
我不能去华盛顿  万一斯塔克先生需要我
I can't go to Washington. Because if Mr. Stark needs me,
我一定得在这儿
then, I have to make sure that I'm here.
你都没见过托尼·斯塔克本人吧
You've never been in the same room as Tony Stark.
等等  怎么了
Wait. What's happening?
彼得不去华盛顿了
Peter's not going to Washington.
-不不  -为什么不去
- No. No, no, no. - Why not?
不是吧  马上就国家赛了
Really? Right before nationals?
他已经退了军乐团和机器人实验室
He already quit marching band and robotics lab.
我不是迷上他了  就是观察力强
I'm not obsessed with him. Just very observant.
弗拉士  你替彼得
Flash, you're in for Peter.
这个嘛  我得先看看我的日程
I don't know. I gotta check my calendar first.
我跟黑寡妇的约会就要到了
I got a hot date with Black Widow coming up.
伪命题
That is false.
不是叫你别乱按铃胡闹吗
What'd I tell you about using the bell for comedic purposes?
-好啊  -你好
- Hey, what's up? - Hey, man.
你好啊  达尔摩先生
What's up, Mr. Delmar?
帕克先生
Mr. Parker.
还是5号  是吗
Number five, right?
嗯  加酸黄瓜
Yeah, and with pickles,
麻烦压得扁扁的  谢谢
and can you smush it down real flat? Thanks.
好嘞
You got it, boss.
你婶婶怎么样了
How's your aunt?
她挺好
Yeah, she's all right.
他婶婶是个很性感的意大利女人
She's a very hot Italian woman.
你女儿怎么样了
How's your daughter?
-10美元  -写着5元啊
- Ten dollars. - It's $5.
叫你嘴贱  10美元
For that comment, $10.
拜托  就是开玩笑
Come on. I'm joking. I'm joking.
给你5美元
Here's $5.
好啊  墨菲
What's up, Murph?
你好吗  伙计
How you doing, buddy?
学校怎么样
So how's school?
无聊啊  我有更好玩的事可做
You know. It's boring. Got better things to do.
要好好上学  孩子  记住
Stay in school, kid. Stay in school.
否则  会落得像我一样
Otherwise, you're gonna end up like me.
-这多棒  -皇后区最好的三明治
- This is great. - Best sandwiches in Queens.
BGM: Blitzkrieg Bop  By  Ramones
可算啊
Finally.
你什么毛病
What's the matter with you?
你能拿一下吗  谢谢
Could you hold this for a second? Thanks.
这是谁的自行车  没人认吗
Is this anybody's bike? No?
-哥们  这是你的自行车吗  -没零钱
- Hey, buddy, is this your bike? - I have no change.
谁有笔吗  你有笔吗
Does anyone have a pen? Do you have a pen?
大家都好吗
Everybody good?
你是油管上那个蜘蛛男  是吧
You're that spider guy on YouTube, right?
叫我蜘蛛侠啦
Call me spider-man!
好啊  蜘蛛侠  翻个身
Okay, spider-man. Do a flip.
-好啊  -不赖
- Yeah! - Not bad.
伙计
Hey, buddy.
别偷车  这可不好
Shouldn't steal cars, it's bad.
这是我的车  蠢蛋
It's my car, dumbass!
快关掉
Shut that off!
-能不能告诉他这是我的车  -我就是...
- Can you tell him it's my car? - I was just--
我还上夜班呢  拜托
I work at nights. Come on.
那不是你的车
That's not your car!
-那是他的车  -我怎么能知道是他的
- That's his car. - How was I supposed to know it's his car?
-他还撬窗  -每天都这么吵吵
- He put that in the window! - Every day with these damn alarms!
-关掉  -别逼我下去收拾你
- Turn it off! - Don't make me come down there, you punk.
加里  你好吗
Hey, Gary! How you doing?
玛乔莉  你好吗  你妈妈好吗
Marjorie, how are you? How's your mother?
我没事
I'm good, I'm good.
已为您接入语音信箱  收件人
You have reached the voicemail box of:
哈皮·霍根
Happy Hogan.
哈皮  跟你报告下今天的战绩
Hey, happy. Here's my report for tonight.
我拦截了一个自行车大盗
I stopped a grand theft bicycle.
但没找到车主  就留了张字条
Couldn't find the owner, so I just left a note.
我还帮助了一位迷路的多米尼加老太太
I helped this lost, old Dominican lady.
她很客气  还给我买了个西班牙油条
She was really nice and bought me a churro.
我就是觉得  我还能做到更多
I just feel like I could be doing more.
我就是想知道下次任务会是什么时候
You know? Just curious when the next real mission's gonna be.
嗯  那打给我哦
So, yeah, just call me back.
我是彼得  帕克
It's Peter. Parker.
干嘛把油条的事说出来啊
Why would I tell him about the churro?
好吧
Okay.
真等不及看看它的威力了
Can't wait to see this thing.
可算有动真格的了
Finally, something good.
有这高科技的玩意简直太轻松了
Yo, this high-tech stuff makes it too easy.
-就说这个值吧  -快来
- Told you it was worth it. - Okay, go, go, go.
漂亮
Nice.
我们今晚还能再劫五个网点
We can hit, like, five more places tonight.
几位好啊  这是忘记卡号了吗
What's up, guys? You forget your pin number?
你们是复仇者诶
You're the Avengers.
你们怎么在这儿
What are you guys doing here?
托儿  绿巨人  可算见到你们了
Thor. Hulk. Good to finally meet you guys.
我以为你们本人会更帅些呢  钢铁侠
I thought you'd be more handsome in person. Iron man.
你抢银行干什么  你是亿万富翁啊
Hey, what are you doing robbing a bank? You're a billionaire.
感觉好怪啊
This feels so weird.
那是什么玩意
What is that thing?
我开始...觉得...
I'm starting...To think...
你们不是...复仇者了
You're not...The Avengers.
911  有什么紧急情况
911. What's your emergency?
蜘蛛侠在大战复仇者联盟
Spider-man is fighting the Avengers
就在21街的一家银行里
in a bank on 21st street.
好了  各位  我们做个了结吧
All right, guys, let's wrap this up.
明天还上学呢
It's a school night.
你这样的混混哪弄来这样的装备的
So how do jerks like you get tech like this?
不  等等
No. Wait, wait, wait!
达尔摩先生
Mr. Delmar.
达尔摩先生  你在吗  有人在吗  有人吗
Mr. Delmar, you in here? Is anybody in here? Hello?
不是吧
Come on.
我得...
I gotta--
-给  -好
- here, here. - Good, yeah.
好的  很好
Okay. Good. Yes.
别别  放下来
Yes-- no. No, put that down.
那可比你我都值钱
That's worth more than you or me.
什么事
Yeah?
哈皮  我刚碰到了特别疯狂的事
Happy, the craziest thing just happened to me.
有群人拿着高科技的武器
These guys were robbing an ATM
打劫了一个自动提款机网点
with high-tech weapons--
慢慢说  我没工夫管小打小闹的
Take a breath. I don't have time for ATM
-劫匪  -但是
- robberies - Yeah, but--
还有你体贴的留言
or the thoughtful notes you leave behind.
我还得操心搬家的事
I have moving day to worry about.
下周前所有东西都得搬走
Everything's gotta be out by next week.
等等  搬家  谁要搬家
Wait, wait. You're moving? Who's moving?
你不看新闻吗
Yeah, don't you watch the news?
托尼卖了复仇者大楼
Tony sold Avengers Tower.
我们将迁至州北的新设施
We're relocating to a new facility upstate
希望  那里的手机信号要烂一些
where hopefully the cell service is much worse.
-那我呢  -你怎么了
- But what about me? - What about you?
那要是斯塔克先生需要我呢
Well, what if Mr. Stark needs me or something
或是发生了什么大事呢
or I don't know, something big goes down?
能不能让我跟斯塔克先生谈谈
Look, can I please just talk to Mr. Stark?
别干什么太危险的事
Look, just stay away from anything too dangerous.
我要负责确保你会负责行事  好吗
I'm responsible for making sure you're responsible, okay?
我很负责的  我...
I am responsible. I--
该死
Crap.
-我的背包没了  -那不像负责的样子
- My backpack's gone. - That doesn't sound responsible.
-我再打给你吧  -不打也行的
- I'll call you back. - Feel free not to.
什么声音
What was that?
没什么  没什么
It's nothing. Nothing.
你是蜘蛛侠
You're the spider-man.
-油管上那个  -我不是
- From YouTube. - I'm not. I'm not.
你刚刚趴在天花板上
You were on the ceiling.
我没有...你为什么在我房间里
No, I wasn't... Man, what are you doing in my room?
梅让我进来的  我们说好一起做完死星的
May let me in. You said we were gonna finish the Death Star.
你不能就这么闯进我的房间
You can't just bust into my room!
那个火鸡肉卷的菜谱太烂了
That Turkey meatloaf recipe is a disaster.
我们出去吃吧  泰国菜行吗
Let's go to dinner. Thai?
内德  吃泰国菜吗
Ned, you want thai?
-好啊  -不好  他还有事
- Yes. - No. He's got a thing.
之后再做
A thing to do after.
好吧
Okay.
穿上点衣服吧
Maybe put on some clothes.
-她还不知道吗  -谁都不知道
- She doesn't know? - Nobody knows.
斯塔克先生知道  因为他给我做了战衣
I mean, Mr. Stark knows because he made my suit.
但没别人了
But that's it.
那是托尼·斯塔克做的  你是复仇者吗
Tony Stark made you that? Are you an Avenger?
是啊  差不多吧
Yeah, basically.
-天呐  -你不能告诉任何人
- Oh, geez. - You can't tell anybody about this.
你得保密
You gotta keep it a secret.
-秘密  为什么  -你知道她的
- Secret? Why? - You know what she's like.
她要是知道我每晚都被人追杀
If she finds out people try and kill me every single night,
她就不会允许我再做下去了
she's not gonna let me do this anymore.
拜托了  内德
Come on, Ned, please.
好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
我跟你说实话
I'll level with you.
我觉得我保不了密
I don't think I can't keep this a secret.
这是我遇到过的最棒的事
It's the greatest thing that's ever happened to me.
内德  梅绝不能知道
Ned, May cannot know.
我现在不能让她那样担心
I cannot do that to her right now.
知道吗
You know?
她经受了那么多事  我...
I mean, everything that's happened with her, I--
求你
Please.
-好吧  -发誓  好吗
- Okay. - Just swear it, okay?
我发誓
I swear.
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this is happening now.
-我能试试战衣吗  -不能
- Can I try the suit on? - No.
它是什么原理  磁铁吗
How's it work? Is it magnets?
那些线你怎么射出来的
How do you shoot the strings?
-明天到学校跟你讲  好吗  -太好了
- I'm gonna tell you about this at school tomorrow, okay? -  Great.
好吧  等一下
Okay, well, wait, then.
你怎么同时做这个和斯塔克的实习
How do you do this and the Stark internship?
这就是斯塔克的实习
This is the Stark internship.
快走吧
Just get out of here.
怎么了
What's the matter?
你不是喜欢肉沙拉吗
Thought you loved larb.
太腻了吗
It's too larby?
不够腻
Not larby enough.
你还要我说几次"腻"
How many times do I have to say "larb" before...
才肯跟我说话
You talk to me?
你知道我爱腻
You know I larb you.
我就是压力大  实习让我好累
I'm just stressed. The internship, and I'm tired.
很忙碌
A lot of work.
斯塔克的实习
The Stark internship.
跟你说  我可不怎么喜欢那个托尼·斯塔克
I have to tell you, not a fan of that Tony Stark.
你总是一心多用  他搞得你心神不宁
You're distracted all the time. He's got you in your head.
深受喜爱的皇后区达尔摩三明治店
...the beloved Queens institution Delmar Sandwiches
他都叫你做什么
What does he have you doing?
在今晚早些时候的一场爆炸中被毁
was destroyed in an explosion earlier tonight
你得相信直觉
You need to use your instincts.
爆炸起因是一场被挫败的自动提款机抢劫
after an ATM robbery was thwarted
而见义勇为的正是皇后区本地的犯罪终结者
by Queens' own colorful local crime stopper,
怎么了
What?
蜘蛛侠
The Spider-man.
蜘蛛侠在阻止他们抢劫的过程中
As the Spider-man attempted to foil their heist,
一股强大的冲击波被触发
a powerful blast was set off,
结果切碎了街对面的小店
slicing through the bodega across the street.
奇迹的是  没人受伤
Miraculously, no one was harmed.
你要是看到了这样的事
If you spot something like that happening,
立刻调头就跑
you turn and you run the other way.
嗯嗯  当然了
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Of course.
离我们就六个街区
Six blocks away from us.
我需要新背包
I need a new backpack.
-什么  -我需要新背包
- What? - I need a new backpack.
这都第五个了
That's five.
-糯米布丁  -我们没点那个
- Sticky rice pudding. - We didn't order that.
请你们的
It's on the house.
谢谢
Thanks.
他真好心
That's nice of him.
我觉得他喜欢腻
I think he larbs you.
你被一只蜘蛛咬了
You got bit by a spider?
能让它咬咬我吗
Can it bite me?
大概挺疼的吧
Well, it probably would've hurt, right?
算了  就算真疼  我也忍了
Whatever. Even if it did hurt, I'd let it bite me.
或许吧  到底多疼
Maybe. How much did it hurt?
那只蜘蛛死了  内德
The spider's dead, Ned.
你当时在场
You were here?
是啊
Yeah.
你可能会没命呢
You could've died.
你下蛋吗
Do you lay eggs?
什么  不
What? No.
-你能吐毒液吗  -不能
- Can you spit venom? - No.
你能召唤一支蜘蛛大军出来吗
Can you summon an army of spiders?
不能  内德
No, Ned.
《索科威亚协议》的签订
The Sokovia Accords were put into place...
你的网能射多远
How far can you shoot your webs?
没试过  闭嘴
It's unknown. Shut up.
开始管理...
--to begin regulating...
我要是你  就站在一栋建筑边缘
If I was you, I would stand on the edge of a building
-尽量往远了射  -闭嘴啦  内德
- and shoot as far as I could-- - Shut up, Ned.
大家好  我是美国队长
I'm Captain America.
不管你是在课堂里  还是战场上
Whether you're in the classroom or on the battlefield...
-你还认识他吗  -嗯  我们见过
- Do you know him too? - Yeah, we met.
-我偷了他的盾  -什么
- I stole his shield. - What?
今天  我的好朋友  你们的体育老师
Today, my good friend, your gym teacher
将带大家进行美国队长健身挑战
will be conducting the Captain America Fitness Challenge.
谢谢  队长
Thank you, captain.
这家伙按说现在是战犯了
Pretty sure this guy's a war criminal now,
但管他呢  我必须给你们看视频
but whatever, I have to show these videos.
是州的要求  我们开始吧
It's required by the state. Let's do it.
复仇者还要缴税吗
Do Avengers have to pay taxes?
绿巨人什么味儿
What does Hulk smell like?
-肯定香香的  -闭嘴吧
- I bet he smells nice. - You have to shut up.
美国队长人挺好吗  还是坏脾气老头那种
Is Captain America cool, or is he like a mean, old grandpa?
内德  别说了  好吗
Ned, just shh, okay?
我能做你的技术支援吗
Can I be your guy in the chair?
什么
What?
就是那个戴着耳机
Yeah. You know how there's a guy with a headset
指挥另一个人行动的人
telling the other guy where to go?
比如  如果你困在了火场里
Like, if you ever stuck in a burning building,
我可以告诉你该去哪
I could tell you where to go.
我可以在一堆屏幕之间周旋
Cause, there'd be screens around me, and I could swivel around them.
我可以做你的技术支援
Cause, I could be your guy in the chair.
内德  我不需要技术支援
Ned, I don't need a guy in the chair.
不错  帕克
Looking good, Parker.
要是我呢  就是上托尔
Now, see, for me, it would be f Thor
嫁钢铁侠  杀绿巨人
marry Iron Man and kill Hulk.
那蜘蛛大侠呢
Well, what about the Spider-man?
就是蜘蛛侠
It's just Spider-man.
你们在油管上看到银行的监控录像了吗
Did you guys see that bank security cam on YouTube?
他打退了四个人
He fought off four guys.
天呐  她喜欢上蜘蛛侠了
Oh, my god, she's crushing on Spider-man.
不会吧
No way.
-有点吧  -恶心
- Kind of. - Oh, gross.
他可能都30了
He's probably, like, 30.
你都不知道他长什么样
You don't know what he looks like.
要是他严重烧伤了呢
What if he's seriously burned?
我不会在乎  我还是会爱他的为人
I wouldn't care. I'd still love him for the person he is inside.
彼得认识蜘蛛侠
Peter knows Spider-man.
不  我不  不...
No, I don't. No. I-- I mean--
他们是朋友
They're friends.
威尔森教练还是美国队长的"好朋友"呢
Yeah, like Coach Wilson and Captain America are friends.
我是见过他  几次
I've met him, yeah. A couple times.
但是
But it's...
是因为斯塔克实习
Through the Stark internship.
但我不该说出来的
Yeah, well, I'm not really supposed to talk about it.
太赞了  这样吧
Well, that's awesome. Hey, you know what?
或许你该请他参加丽兹的派对  是吧
Maybe you should invite him to Liz's party. Right?
是啊  我今晚请大家来玩的
Yeah, um, I'm having people over tonight.
非常欢迎你也来
You're more than welcome to come.
-开派对吗  -是啊  会很赞的
- Having a party? - Yeah, it's gonna be dope.
你真该把你的私密好友蜘蛛侠也请来
You should totally invite your personal friend Spider-man.
算了
It's okay.
我知道彼得反正也忙得没时间参加派对
I know Peter's way too busy for parties anyway, so...
得了  他会去的  是吧  帕克
Come on. He'll be there. Right, Parker?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
帮你忙
Helping you out.
你没听到她说吗
Did you not hear her?
丽兹喜欢你
Liz has a crush on you.
哥们  你是个复仇者
Dude, you're an Avenger.
要说我们中谁有机会约到高四女生  就是你了
If any one of us has a chance with a senior girl, it's you.
郊区的家庭派对
House party in the suburbs.
这我记得  好嫉妒
I remember these. Kind of jealous.
今晚会难以忘怀
It'll be a night to remember.
内德  有些帽子挑人  那顶帽子很衬你
Ned, some hats wear men. You wear that hat.
嗯  它能给我自信
Yeah, it gives me confidence.
这是个错误
This is a mistake.
我们还是回家吧
Let's just go home.
彼得
Peter.
我知道  我知道这很难
I know. I know it's really hard
努力融入的同时  眼看着自己的身体发生变化
trying to fit in with all the changes your body's going through.
你正在萌发
It's flowering now.
他最近压力好大
He's so stressed out lately.
去参加派对很能减压的
What helps with stress is a party.
-我们去吧  -嗯  我们去吧
- We should go to the party. - Yeah, let's do it.
我去了  我去了
Yeah, I'm gonna go. I'm gonna go.
彼得
Peter...
-好好玩  好吗  -好啊
- Have fun, okay? - I will.
再见  梅
Bye, May.
哥们  你带战衣了吧
Dude, you have the suit, right?
我们的人生要就此改变了
This is gonna change our lives.
DJ弗拉士
DJ Flash.
好  让蜘蛛侠飞进来
Okay. We're gonna have Spider-man swing in,
然后说你们关系很好
say you guys are tight,
然后跟我撞个拳  或来个那种哥们半抱
and I get a fist bump or one of those half bro-hugs.
真不敢相信你们也来这个没劲的派对了
Can't believe you're at this lame party.
你不也来了吗
But you're here too.
我来了吗
Am I?
天呐
Oh, my gosh.
你们好啊  帽子真帅  内德
Hey, guys. Cool hat, Ned.
-好啊  丽兹  -好啊  丽兹
- Hi, Liz. - Hi, Liz.
你们来我太高兴了
I'm so happy you guys came.
有披萨  有酒  别客气
There's pizza and drinks. Help yourself.
-派对真棒  -谢谢
- What a great party. - Thanks.
要是真打破了什么  我爸妈会杀了我的
I-- my parents will kill me if anything's broken.
-我得去...  -嗯
- I gotta-- - Yeah.
好好玩
Have fun.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
哥们  你干什么呢
Dude, what are you doing?
她就在这儿  快去扮成蜘蛛
She's here. Spider it up.
不不  我不能这么做
No, no, no. I can't-- I cannot do this.
蜘蛛侠不是派对猴戏  好吗
Spider-man is not a party trick, okay?
我就做我自己吧
Look, I'm just gonna be myself.
彼得  没人想看那个
Peter, no one wants that.
老铁
Dude.
软蛋·帕克  你好啊
Penis Parker, what's up?
你的好哥们蜘蛛侠呢
So where's your pal Spider-man?
我猜猜  跟你的假想女友在加拿大吗
Let me guess: In Canada with your imaginary girlfriend?
那不是蜘蛛侠啊
That's not Spider-man.
那是穿红衬衫的内德
That's just Ned in a red shirt.
好啊  我是蜘蛛侠
"Hey, what's up? I'm Spider-man.
就是路过跟我哥们彼得打个招呼
Just thought I'd swing by and say hello to my buddy Peter.
内德  好啊  彼得人呢
What's up, Ned? Hey, where's Peter, anyways?
他就在附近吧
He must be around..."
天呐  这真蠢
God, this is stupid.
我在干什么
What am I doing?
搞什么
What the hell?
真烦人
This sucks.
这是用在索科威亚回收的
Now, this is crafted from a reclaimed
奥创手臂制作的
sub-Ultron arm straight from Sokovia.
给  你试试看
Here. You try.
哥们  我只想要点低调的东西
Man, I wanted something low-key.
你干吗卖我这些高档货
Why are you trying to upsell me, man?
好吧  我有符合你要求的
Okay, okay. I got what you need, all right?
我这里有一堆好东西
I got tons of great stuff here.
稍等
One sec.
我有黑洞手榴弹  齐塔瑞磁轨炮
Okay, I got black hole grenades, Chitauri railguns...
你还在野外乱开火了  快点吧
You letting off shots in public now? Hurry up.
时代变了
Look, times are changing.
只有我们卖这些个高科技武器
We're the only ones selling these high-tech weapons.
自动提款机劫匪肯定就从他们这儿买的武器
This must be where the ATM robbers got their stuff.
我只是想要打劫的家伙事
I just need something to stick up somebody.
我没想把他们打回到过去
I'm not trying to shoot them back in time.
我有反重力攀爬器
I got antigrav climbers.
攀爬器
Yo, climbers?
那是什么鬼动静
Okay, what the hell is that?
-这是你布的局吗  -冷静  哥们
- Did you set us up? - Hey, hey, man.
喂喂  你想开枪  就冲我来吧
Come on. You gonna shoot at somebody, shoot at me.
好啊
All right.
那是什么
What was that?
-我们得联系他  -不用
- We gotta call him. - No, no, no, no.
你又乱开火了吗
Did you just do it again?
-闭嘴  -我要打给他
- Shut up. - I'm calling him.
图姆斯电话
Toomes's phone.
老大
Boss.
我的屁股
Oh, my butt!
这可好  那我得走捷径了
Great. Guess I'm gonna have to take a shortcut.
两位  打得好  玩得开心点
Hey, guys. Good game. Have fun.
乖狗狗
Buddy.
抱歉  没工夫玩  去捡
Sorry, no time to play. Here, go fetch.
这才像话嘛
Now, this is more like it.
好香
Smells really good.
这电影真棒
Great movie!
你们好啊
Hey, guys.
我是彼得  请留言
Hey, it's Peter. Leave a message.
彼得  你去哪了
Peter, where are you?
帽子没给我加分  你这样可不好
The hat's not working. This is not cool.
差一点
Almost got you.
以为你甩掉我了  是吧
Thought you got away from me, didn't you?
我早料到你会到这儿了
I got you right where I want you.
惊不惊喜
Surprise!
怎么回事
What the hell?
然后他像个怪物似的一个猛子扎下来
And then he just, like, swooped down like a monster
抱起了我
and picked me up,
带我飞了好高  然后又把我丢了下来
and took me up like a thousand feet and just dropped me.
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
你在我的战衣上装了追踪器吗
Did you put a tracker in my suit or something?
我在你的战衣上什么都装了
I put everything in your suit.
包括这个加热器
Including this heater.
舒服多了  谢谢
That's better. Thanks.
你怎么想的啊
What were you thinking?
那个带翅膀的男人显然是武器的源头
The guy with wings is obviously the source of the weapons.
我得拿下他
I gotta take him down.
还拿下他呢
Take him down now, huh?
别冲动  这种事是有专人负责管的
Steady Crockett, there are people who handle this sort of thing.
-复仇者吗  -不不
- The Avengers? - No, no, no.
这种事不值得他们出手
This is a little below their pay grade.
总之  斯塔克先生  您不必大老远赶来的
Anyway, Mr. Stark, you didn't have to come all the way out here.
我刚刚能搞定的  我没事的
I had that. I was fine.
我没赶来
I'm not here.
幸好这地方有无线网络
Thank god this place has Wi-Fi
否则你现在就死翘翘了
or you would be toast right now.
顺便也感谢象鼻神吧
Thank Ganesh while you're at it.
谢谢
Cheers.
拜托你别管那个会飞的秃鹫男了
Look, forget the flying vulture guy, please.
-为什么  -还为什么
- Why? - Why?
因为我说了
Because I said so!
抱歉  教训小孩子呢
Sorry, I'm talking to a teenager.
脚踏实地
Stay close to the ground.
先帮助小人物  循序渐进
Build up your game helping the little people,
比如那个给你买油条的老太太
like that lady that bought you the churro.
你不能就做个友善的
Can't you just be a friendly
好街坊蜘蛛侠吗
neighborhood Spider-man?
但我现在已经准备好承担更多责任了
But I'm ready for more than that now.
不  你没有
No, you're not.
我迎战美国队长时  你可不是这么想的
That is not what you thought when I took on Captain America.
相信我  孩子
Trust me, kid.
要是美队真想打趴你  他是做得到的
If cap wanted to lay you out, he would've.
听我说
Listen to me.
你要是再碰到这些武器  联系哈皮
If you come across these weapons again, call Happy.
你在开车吗
Are you driving?
考虑大学的事永远不嫌早
You know, it's never too early to start thinking about college.
我在麻省理工有关系  结束通话
I got some pull at MIT. End call.
不  我不需要去大学
No, I don't need to go to col...
-斯塔克先生  -斯塔克先生已断线
- Mr. Stark. - Mr. Stark is no longer connected.
这可好
That's awesome.
"脚踏实地"  他说什么呢
"Stay close to the ground"? What is he talking about?
伙计  怎么了  我正要回去
Man, what's up? I'm on my way back.
其实  我是打来告诉你  你还是别来了
Actually, I was calling to say maybe you shouldn't come.
-大家听着  -听啊
- Everyone. - Listen to this.
我说"软蛋"  你们说"帕克
When I say "Penis," you say "Parker."
-软蛋  -帕克
- Penis! - Parker!
抱歉  彼得  看来我们还是那么可悲
Sorry, Peter. I guess we're still losers.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天学校见
I'll see you tomorrow in school.
白痴
Idiots.
Idiots!
老大  你老婆一直在给你发短信
Boss? Your wife keeps texting you.
什么刹车灯的事
Something about a brake light.
我不是叫你别看我的手机吗
What'd I tell you about looking at my phone?
抱歉  你就搁在这儿了
Sorry. You left it out.
你知道我这人天生好奇
You know I'm a curious person by nature.
我设计好那个高空真空密封装置了
I finished designing that high-altitude vacuum seal.
如果你想...干票大的的话
In case you want to, you know, go for the big one?
你还在研究那个  我说不行了
You're still on that? I told you, no.
不行的  别想了
The answer's no. Forget it.
刚刚太帅了
I mean, that was badass.
我跟你说多少次了
How many times have I told you
别在外面乱开火
not to fire them out in the open?
-你叫我卖掉货的  -低调卖
- You said, move the merchandise. - Under the radar.
低调卖
Under the radar!
这样我们才能生存下去
That's how we survive.
你要是招来了损害控制
If you bring Damage Control
或是复仇者  我们就完了
or the Avengers down here, we're through.
你在外面  戴着那个傻兮兮的玩意
You're out there wearing that goofy thing,
到处炸车  还自称"惊悚"
lighting up cars calling yourself the Shocker.
我是惊悚  我以惊制人
"I'm the shocker. I shock people."
这是职业摔跤吗
What is this, pro wrestling?
随你说吧  老头子  行了
Whatever, old man. Come on.
听着
Look.
我知道你是什么都不在乎
I know you don't give a crap about anything.
但我在乎
But I do.
我建立这里
I built this whole place
就是为了照顾我要照顾的人
because I got people I have to look after.
嗯嗯
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你知道吗
You know what?
我受不起你的胡闹
I can't afford your bullshit.
-滚  -什么
- Get out of here. - What?
你完了  你被踢出去了
You're done. You're off the crew.
好吧
Yeah, all right.
All right.
但你赶我出去能放心吗
Wonder if you can afford me out there, though, right?
我知道那么多事
With everything I know.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我就是说  或许你妻子会想知道
I'm just saying, maybe your wife would like to know
你的钱究竟是哪来的
where you really get your money from.
-你知道吗  -什么
- You know what? - What?
你说的对
You're right.
-那个好使吗  -我不知道
- That work? - I don't know.
我是不放心
I can't afford that.
等等
W-w-wait.
我去
Damn.
这不是反重力枪吗
I thought this was the antigravity gun.
什么  不  那个才是
What? No, that's that one.
给
Here.
现在你是惊悚了
Now you're the shocker.
去把他丢的武器找回来
Go out there and find that weapon he lost.
好
All right.
谢谢你抛下我了
Thanks for bailing on me.
突然有事嘛
Yeah, well, something came up.
那是什么啊
What is that?
我不知道  有人企图拿它蒸发了我
I don't know. Some guy tried to vaporize me with it.
-真的  -嗯
- Seriously? - Yeah.
赞啊
Awesome.
不赞  那人太过分了
I mean, not awesome. Totally uncool of that guy.
-真吓人  -是啊
- So scary. - Yeah.
我觉得这是个能源
Well, look, I think it's a power source.
是啊  但它连着各种微处理器
Yeah, but it's connected to all these microprocessors.
那是感应充电板
That's an inductive charging plate.
我就用那个给我的牙刷充电
That's what I use to charge my toothbrush.
做这些武器的人
Whoever's making these weapons
显然是结合了外星和人类的科技
is obviously combining alien tech with ours.
这真是史上最酷的一句话了
That is literally the coolest sentence anyone has ever said.
我只想感谢你
I just want to thank you
让我加入你的旅途
for letting me be part of your journey
进入这神奇的...
into this amazing--
手指别往刀刃上送
Keep your fingers clear of the blades.
我得查明这玩意是什么  是谁做的
I gotta figure out what this thing is and who makes it.
我们下课后去实验室做些测试
We'll go to the lab after class and run some tests.
好
Let's do it.
首先  我觉得该用质谱仪分析一下发光物
First, I said we put the glowy thing in the mass spectrometer.
首先  我们得想个比"发光物"更好的名字
First, we gotta come up with a better name than "glowy thingy."
是啊
You're right.
该死
Crap.
过来
Come on, come on, come on.
高中真让我不舒服
High schools creep me out.
有种奇怪的味儿  知道吗
They got this funny smell, you know what I mean?
那是企图杀我的人之一
Hey, that's one of the guys that tried to kill me.
-什么  -是啊
- What? - Yeah.
我们得赶紧跑
We gotta get out of here.
不不
No, no, no.
我得跟上他们
I gotta follow them.
或许他们能引我找到把我丢进湖里的人
Maybe they can lead me to the guy that dropped me in the lake.
有人把你丢进了湖里
Someone dropped you in a lake?
是啊  那滋味可不好受
Yeah, it was not good.
-彼得  -不  待在这里  内德
- Peter-- - No. Stay there, Ned.
彼得
Peter.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
没什么
Nothing.
嗯  你挺好吗
Yeah. You good?
下象棋呢
Chess.
要是老大知道我们在哪
Man, can you imagine what the boss would say
他会怎么说啊
if he knew where we were?
读数显示这里有能量脉冲
It's saying there was an energy pulse here.
但武器不在
There's no sign of the weapon.
就算之前在  现在也不在了
And even if it was here, now it's gone.
我们也走吧
So are we.
这好赞
This is so awesome.
是吧
I know, right?
他们在布鲁克林
They're in Brooklyn.
斯塔顿岛
Staten Island.
离开泽西了
Leaving Jersey.
他们停下了
They stopped.
马里兰州
Maryland?
-那里有什么  -我不知道
- What's there? - I don't know.
邪恶老巢吗
Evil lair?
-他们有老巢  -哥们
- They have a lair? - Dude,
一个鼓捣外星武器  老大长翅膀的团伙
a gang with alien guns run by a guy with wings?
他们绝对有老巢啊
Yeah, they have a lair.
厉害
Badass.
但你要怎么过去啊  离这儿有300英里呢
But how are you gonna get there if it's, like, 300 miles away?
离华盛顿不远
It's not too far from D.C.
-是彼得  -各位
- It's Peter. - Guys.
-彼得  -好啊  伙计
- Peter? - Hey, buddy.
我希望  我还能归队
Yeah, I was hoping maybe I could rejoin the team.
不行  你不能突然退出
No, no way. You can't quit on us,
然后又大摇大摆地回来  还指望大家都欢迎你
stroll up and be welcomed back by everyone.
欢迎回来  彼得
Welcome back, Peter!
弗拉士  你还做回第一替补
Flash, you're back to first alternate.
-什么  -他要占你的位子
- What? - He's taking your place.
那个  我们能不能走了
Excuse me, can we go already?
我想在晚餐之前去哪个大使馆
I was hoping to get in some light protesting
小小抗议一会儿
in front of one of the embassies before dinner.
抗议是爱国行为  我们上大巴吧
Protesting is patriotic. Let's get on the bus.
大家注意了
Focus up, everyone.
下一话题  土星卫星
Our next topic is the moons of Saturn.
热力学第二定律
Second law of thermodynamics.
弗兰克·辛纳屈
Frank Sinatra.
萨姆特堡
Fort Sumter.
-弗拉士说错了  -好了  大家专心
- Flash is wrong. - Okay, guys, let's focus.
-下一个  -丽兹  别累着他们了
- Next one. - Liz, don't overwork 'em.
锶  钡  振金
Strontium, barium, vibranium.
很好  彼得  很高兴你能回来
Very good, Peter. Glad to have you back.
很高兴能回来
Glad to be back.
目前的标准...
What is the current standard unit of--?
我能去接个电话吗
Can I take this real quick?
-很快的  -去吧
- I'll only be a sec. - Yeah, fine.
喂
Hello?
我屏幕的光点显示  你是出纽约了
Got a blip on my screen here. You left New York?
-好了  各位注意  -追踪器
- Okay, focus up, everyone. - Tracker.
是啊  学校旅行  没事的
Yeah, it's just a school trip. It's nothing.
哈皮  我得说
Look, Happy, I gotta say,
你这样不经我允许追踪我
you tracking me without permission
完全侵犯了我的隐私
is a complete violation of my privacy.
-那不一样  -什么不一样
- That's different. - What's different?
没什么  听着  只是学术竞赛而已
Nothing. Look, it's just the academic decathlon.
不是什么大事
It's no big deal.
是不是大事我说了算
I'll decide if it's no big deal.
听起来的确不是大事
Sounds like it's no big deal,
但你记住  我在看着你
but remember, I'm watching you.
-大家跟紧了  -对
- Everyone stick together. - Yeah.
你逗我吗  这地方好大
You kidding me? This place is huge.
-我见过更大的  -里面有只鸟
- I've seen bigger. - There's a bird in here.
你带电脑了吧
You brought your laptop, right?
干什么
Why?
彼得
Peter,
为什么要去掉你战衣上的追踪器
why are we removing the tracker from your suit?
因为我要在这些人再次转移前
Because I gotta follow these guys to their boss
跟着他们找到他们的老大
before they move again
而且我不想让斯塔克先生知道
and I don't really want Mr. Stark to know about it.
你要对钢铁侠撒谎
So you're lying to Iron Man now?
不  不是撒谎
No, I'm not lying.
他只是还不知道我的能耐
He just doesn't really get what I can do yet.
好了
Gotcha.
好了  哈皮  追踪台灯去吧
All right, Happy, enjoy tracking this lamp.
这里还有一堆其他的子系统
There's a ton of other subsystems in here.
但都被辅助轮协议禁用了
But they're all disabled by the Training Wheels Protocol.
什么
What?
辅助轮协议
"Training Wheels Protocol"?
关掉
Turn it off.
这样不好吧
I don't think that's a good idea.
禁用大概是有原因的
I mean, they're probably blocked for a reason.
拜托  我不需要辅助轮
Come on, man, I don't need training wheels.
我受够了他一直把我当小孩
I'm sick of him treating me like a kid all the time.
-太过分了  -但你确实是小孩
- It's not cool. - But you are a kid.
是啊  一个能徒手拦下大巴的小孩
Yeah, a kid who can stop a bus with his bare hands.
彼得  我觉得这样做不好
Peter, I just don't think this is a great idea.
要是是违法的怎么办
I mean, what if this is illegal?
求你了
Look, please.
这是我证明自己的机会
This is my chance to prove myself.
我能行的  内德  来吧
I can handle it. Ned, come on.
我真觉得这样不好
I really don't think this is a good idea.
技术支援啊
The guy in the chair.
-别勾我  -来吧
- Don't do that. - Come on.
发光物是证据  保管好  好吗
The glowy thing, it's evidence. Keep it safe, all right?
好  好
Okay. Okay.
-他们在移动  -小心点
- They're moving. - Be careful.
-丽兹  -时间掐得刚好
- Hey, Liz. - Perfect timing.
我们要去游泳
We're gonna go swimming.
-快来  快来  -什么
- Come on, come on. - What?
彼得
Hey, Peter.
我正要去商务中心学习
I was-- I was gonna go study in the business center.
彼得  你不用学习了
Peter, you don't need to study.
你是我认识的最聪明的人
You're, like, the smartest guy I've ever met.
而且  比赛前一天
And besides, a rebellious group activity
集体进行反叛活动  有助于鼓舞士气
the day before competition is good for morale.
我在TED演讲里读到的
Well, I read that in a Ted talk, so--
我在TED演讲里听到的
I-- I heard it in a Ted talk.
我还读了本指导技巧书
And I read a coaching book.
你真的  这次竞赛对你真的很重要
Are you really-- this is really important to you.
是啊  这是我们的未来
Yeah. It's our future.
我不想搞砸
I'm not gonna screw it up.
而且  我们席卷了小冰箱
Besides, we raided the minibar
这些巧克力棒11美元呢
and these candy bars were, like, $11.
换上泳衣快来吧
So get your trunks on and come on.
来吧
Come on.
-来吧  -我来了  来了
- Come on. - I'm coming, I'm coming.
走吧
Let's go.
晚上好  彼得
Good evening, Peter.
喂  谁啊
Hello? Hello?
祝贺你完成了
Congratulations on completing
严格的辅助轮协议
the rigorous training wheels protocol
可以使用本战衣的所有功能了
and gaining access to your suit's full capabilities.
谢谢
Thank you.
你今晚要带我去哪
So, where would you like to take me tonight?
我在某个人身上放了追踪器  他是坏人
I put a tracker on someone. He's a bad guy.
追踪器已锁定
Tracker located.
拦截目标路线规划中
Plotting course to intercept target.
好  只要我能在学术竞赛前
Okay, well, as long as I make it back
赶回来就行
in time for decathlon, it's fine.
距离目的地还有一百米  正在接近
One hundred meters from destination and closing.
跳
Jump now.
检测到三个人
Detecting three individuals.
他们的秘密据点竟然在加油站  逊爆了
Why is their secret lair in a gas station? That's so lame.
战衣姐姐  他们在干什么
Suit lady, what are they doing?
你想听到他们在说什么吗
Do you want to hear what they're saying?
我能听到他们在说什么  好啊
I can hear what they're saying? Uh, yeah.
启动强化侦查模式
Activating enhanced reconnaissance mode.
这铁臂是我在拉各斯清理行动中找到的
I got the gauntlet from the Lagos cleanup.
-剩下是我自己设计的  -真酷
- The rest is my design. - Whoa, that's so cool.
不敢相信他们还在清理三曲翼总部
Can't believe they're still cleaning the Triskelion mess.
我喜欢  他们一直闯祸
I love it. They keep making messes,
-我们就一直有财发  -目标到达
- we keep getting rich. - Target inbound.
他们正在打劫
They're in the middle of a heist.
我能抓他们个现行  太棒了
I could catch 'em all red-handed. This is awesome.
好了  我要靠近一些
Okay, I'm gonna get a little closer
好看清情况
so I can see what's happening.
要我启动强化战斗模式吗
Would you like me to engage enhanced combat mode?
强化战斗模式  好啊
"Enhanced combat mode"? Yeah.
启动击杀功能
Activating instant kill.
不不  我不想杀人
No, no, no, no. I don't want to kill anybody.
关闭击杀功能
Deactivating instant kill.
你们听见了吗
Did you hear that?
刚刚怎么了  怎么回事
What the hell just happened? What was that?
你从招牌上跳了下来  脸冲下落地了
You jumped off the sign and landed on your face.
战衣姐姐  我的射网器怎么了
Suit Lady, what's wrong with my web-shooters?
飞射是强化战斗模式的默认模式
Rapid-fire is the default for enhanced combat mode.
我干吗要飞射
Why would I need rapid-fire?
你想看看更多选项吗
Would you like to see more options?
你共有576种射网选择
You have 576 possible web-shooter combinations.
斯塔克先生做得太过了
Mr. Stark really overdid it.
你俩等在这里
You two wait right here.
等等  你最好打开减震器
Wait. You're gonna want to turn on the dampers
否则那玩意会震碎你的胳膊
or that thing will shatter your arm.
好吧  减震器在哪
All right, where's the dampers?
-那个  -选得好
- That one. - Great choice.
要我把这个设成你的新默认模式吗
Would you like me to set this as your new default?
-不不  -摁下去
- No, no, no. - Push that in.
-这里吗  -不是  另一个
- Right here? - No, the other--
-这个吗  -对  摁下去
- This one right here? - Yeah, push it.
-那又是什么  -电击蛛网
- What was that? - Taser webs.
电击蛛网  我不想要电击蛛网
Taser webs? I don't want taser webs.
你似乎对你的射网器设置很不熟悉
You seem to be unfamiliar with your web-shooter settings.
要进行一次复习课程吗
Would you like to run a refresher course?
-不  你选吧  -好的
- No. Just-- you choose. - Sure thing.
6A9  你正点运行吗
Six-Alpha-niner, are you running on time?
收到  中心  6A9正点运行
Copy, central. Six-Alpha-niner on schedule.
-我看到了  -行动  行动
- I got a visual. - Green light, green light.
那是他
That's him.
好  我看到车队了
Okay. I got eyes on the convoy.
正在靠近最后一辆
Pulling in behind the caboose.
下锚
Deploy anchors.
进入
Dropping down.
没有发出求救信号  开始行动
No outgoing distress signals. You're all clear.
看来这里有些好东西啊
Looks like they got some good stuff here.
酷啊  似乎是某种物质移相器
Cool. It's like some kind of matter phase shifter.
好了  我上来了
All right, coming up.
大鸟  这不是你的
Big bird! This doesn't belong to you.
天呐
Oh, god.
-战衣姐姐  那是什么  -你叫我选的
- Suit Lady, what was that? - You told me to choose.
什么  都设成正常的就好
What? No, just set everything back to normal.
启动所有系统
Activating all systems.
我的头啊
My head.
你似乎轻微脑震荡了
You appear to have a mild concussion.
我现在在哪
So where am I right now?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
集装箱壁隔绝了我的传感器
The container walls are hindering my sensors.
等等
Wait a minute.
他们肯定是劫持了卡车
They must have hijacked the truck
把我带回了他们的邪恶老巢
and taken me to their evil lair.
好吧  战衣姐姐
Okay, Suit Lady,
这次我们得杀出一条血路了
we're gonna have to fight our way out of this one.
三  二  一
Three, two, one!
这是什么地方
What is this place?
战衣姐姐  我在哪
Suit Lady, where am I?
你在东海岸最安全的设施内
You're in the most secure facility on the eastern seaboard.
损害控制储存库
The Damage Control deep storage vault.
不  不是吧
No. Seriously?
大门应该是到早上才会开启
The door will most likely remain closed until morning.
早上
Morning?
战衣姐姐  我觉得不该
Suit Lady, I kind of feel bad
一直喊你"战衣姐姐"  知道吗
calling you "Suit Lady," you know?
我或许该给你起个名字
I think I should probably give you a name...
比如丽兹  不不
Like Liz. No, no, no.
天呐  那太怪了
God, that's-- that's weird.
凯伦呢
What about Karen?
如果你想  可以喊我凯伦
You can call me Karen if you would like.
凯伦  战衣还有什么功能
Karen, what else can this suit do?
什么
What?
或许我们该运行一下复习课程
Maybe we should run that refresher course.
-弹跳蛛网  -弹跳蛛网
- Ricochet web. - Ricochet web.
酷
Cool.
分流蛛网
Splitter web.
-蛛网手雷  -蛛网手雷
- Web grenade. - Web grenade!
我该告诉丽兹我是蜘蛛侠吗
Should I tell Liz that I'm Spider-man?
丽兹是谁
Who is Liz?
丽兹是谁  她...
Who's Liz? She's--
她最棒了  她好赞
She's the best. She's awesome.
她是我们学校的一个姑娘
She's just a girl who goes to my school.
而且
And, uh...
我真的很想告诉她
Yeah, I just-- I really want to tell her,
但这有点怪怪的
but it's kind of weird, you know?
"我是蜘蛛侠"
"I'm-- I'm Spider-man."
这有什么奇怪的
What's weird about that?
要是她以为我会是托尼·斯塔克那样的人呢
What if she's expecting someone like Tony Stark?
等她看到是我  得多失望啊
Imagine how disappointed she'd be when she sees me.
如果我是她
Well, if I were her,
我就一点不会失望
I wouldn't be disappointed at all.
谢谢  凯伦
Thanks, Karen.
真高兴有人能聊聊
It's really nice to have somebody to talk to.
我们在这里待多久了
How long we been here anyways?
-37分钟  -什么
- Thirty-seven minutes. - What?
37分钟  这不可能
Thirty-seven minutes? That's insane.
我再也受不了了
I cannot take this anymore.
我得出去
I got to-- I gotta get out of here.
这里肯定有什么我能用的
There's got to be something in here I can use.
我看看
Okay, let's see.
不行
Nope.
这个好赞
That's awesome.
这就像那个发光物
It's like the glowy thing.
那个发光物是爆炸性齐塔瑞能量核
That glowy thing is an explosive Chitauri energy core.
你是说我们一直到处带着枚炸弹
You mean, we've been carrying around a bomb?
得有辐射才会让它
It would require radiation to transform it
进入易爆状态
into an explosive state.
不不
No, no, no, no, no.
拜托  谁来放我出去
Please! Please, somebody, let me out!
凯伦  你得帮我超控那个时间锁
Karen, you have to help me override that time lock.
好  凯伦  降低电压  运行一下
Okay, Karen, lower the voltage and run it.
试验不成功
Trial unsuccessful.
好吧  我们只能把所有组合都试一遍了
Okay, we're just gonna have to try every sequence.
内德  彼得  我们要迟了  走吧
Ned, Peter, we're gonna be late. Come on, let's go.
好  等等
Okay. Hold on, hold on.
第247次试验
Initiating trial 247.
成功了  成功了
It worked. It works!
务必关闭所有手机
Please be sure all cell phones are turned off.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯伦  你得尽快送我去竞赛场地
Karen, you have to get me to the decathlon as fast as possible.
好的  告诉我在哪
Sure thing. Just tell me where it is.
就在华盛顿纪念碑街对面
It's right across the street from the Washington Monument.
我是内德  请留言
It's Ned. Leave a message.
内德  给我打电话  那个发光物是炸弹
Ned, call me back! The glowy thing's a bomb!
你右边有辆车靠近
There's a vehicle approaching on your right.
我们进入了赛点
We have now entered sudden death.
下一个回答正确者将赢下冠军
The next correct answer wins the championship.
中城区科技高中
Midtown tech?
Zero.
正确
That is correct.
中城区拿下冠军
Midtown takes the championship!
我们赢了
We won!
各位  我好为你们骄傲
You guys, I am so proud of you.
就说我们不需要彼得吧
Told you we didn't need Peter.
弗拉士  你一个问题都没答过
Flash, you didn't answer a single question.
-在感受气氛呢  米歇尔  -是啊
- Taking it all in, Michelle? - Oh, yeah, I just--
我不太想颂扬奴隶建造的东西
I don't want to celebrate something that was built by slaves.
华盛顿纪念碑不会是...
I'm sure the Washington Monument wasn't built by--
好吧
Okay.
-好好看书吧  -谢谢
- Enjoy your book. - Thanks.
-内德  你还活着  -彼得  你没事吧
- Ned, you're alive! - Peter, are you okay?
内德  发光物呢  发光物
Ned, Ned, where's the glowy thing? The glowy thing?
别担心  安全着呢  在我背包里
Don't worry, it's safe. It's in my backpack.
不  内德  听着
No, Ned, listen!
不  内德  发光物是危险品
No, no, Ned, the glowy thing is dangerous!
你错过了竞赛
You missed the decathlon.
-我替你掩护了  -内德  听我说
- I covered for you. - Ned, listen to me!
我们在华盛顿纪念碑
We're at the Washington Monument...
-彼得  是你吗  -丽兹
- Peter, is that you? - Hey, Liz.
-那是丽兹吗  -请让内德接电话
- Is that Liz? - Please, put Ned back on the phone.
-你该把你的感觉告诉她  -你不见人影
- You should tell her how you feel. - You flake!
幸好我们赢了
You are so lucky we won.
我想生你气  但我更加担心
You know, I want to be mad, but I'm more worried.
你是怎么回事啊
Like, what is going on with you?
丽兹  我得跟内德讲话  真的是要紧事
Liz, I have to talk to Ned. It's really important!
小姐  请把东西都放在传送带上
Miss, all items on the belt, please.
丽兹  内德背包里有样东西
Liz, there's something in Ned's backpack!
非常危险  千万不能过X光
It's really dangerous. Don't let it go through an X-ray.
丽兹  丽兹  该死
Liz? Liz! Damn it.
哈林顿老师  能让我去告诉彼得他被开除了吗
Mr. Harrington, can I be the one to tell Peter he's expelled?
华盛顿纪念碑高169.29米
The Washington Monument is 555 feet, five and one-eighth inches tall.
可以看到大理石和花岗岩
Notice how the marble and granite
沿着石块周围被切开
are cut around the stone.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
不不不  凯伦  上面什么情况
No, no, no. Karen, what's going on up there?
齐塔瑞能量核爆炸了
The Chitauri core has detonated
导致电梯结构严重受损
and caused severe structural damage to the elevator.
-糟糕  -我的朋友在上面
- Oh, no. - My friends are up there.
什么  别担心  女士  一切都会没事的
What? Don't worry, ma'am, everything's gonna be okay.
借过  借过  天呐  好高啊
Excuse me, excuse me. Oh, my god, that's tall.
天呐  看天花板
Oh, my god. Look at the ceiling.
大家冷静
Just stay calm, everyone.
我们都要死在这里了
We are all going to die here.
预计10分钟后将发生致命失效
Estimating 10 minutes before catastrophic failure.
我们完蛋了
We're freakin' screwed.
好了  各位  我知道那很吓人
Okay, guys, I know that was scary,
但我们的安全系统还好使
but our safety systems are working.
安全系统已完全失效
The safety systems are completely failing.
我们在这里很安全
We're very safe in here.
电梯内的人面临即刻的死亡威胁
The occupants are in imminent mortal danger.
我已经尽快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
来吧  把手递给我
Let's go. Give me your hand.
125秒后将发生致命失效
You now have 125 seconds until catastrophic failure.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
意外动作导致了情况加速恶化
Unexpected motion has caused the deterioration to escalate.
我怎么进去
How do I get in there?
启动侦查无人机
Activating reconnaissance drone.
那个一直在我胸前吗  太赞了
Has that been there this whole time? That's awesome.
寻找最佳进入口
Locating optimal entry point.
前往西南窗口
Proceed to southwest window.
凯伦  我就去
Karen, I'm on my way.
-这里有好多玻璃  -你行的
- There's a lot of glass here. - You got this.
继续
Keep coming, keep coming.
好了  天呐
Okay. Oh, my god.
好了
Okay.
怎么了  你已经到达西南窗口了
What's wrong? You've reached the southwest window.
-你为什么犹豫不前  -没事
- Why are you hesitating? - It's fine.
我就是从没爬过这么高
I've just never been this high before.
而且你还没有重装你的降落伞
You have also not reinstalled your parachute,
如果从这么高掉下去  很可能会致命
so a fall from this height would most likely be lethal.
太好了
Perfect.
天呐
Oh, my god.
它怎么不碎
Why is it not breaking?
是10厘米厚的防弹玻璃
It's four-inch ballistic glass.
你得制造更大的动量
You'll have to create more momentum.
这里是特区警察  上报身份
This is D.C. Metro police. Identify yourself.
我朋友在里面呢  快停下
My friends are in there! My friends are in there! Stop!
立刻回到地面上
Return to the ground immediately.
-下一个谁  -我  到我了
- Okay, who's next? - Me, it's my turn!
弗拉士  不是吧  你干什么呢
Flash, seriously? What are you doing?
-上去吧  -别管奖杯了
- Come on. - Don't worry about the trophy.
退下
Stand down!
立刻回到地面上
Return to the ground immediately!
回到地面上  否则我们开火了
Return to the ground or we will open fire!
上去  上去
Go up, go up.
我行的
I got this.
拿着我的奖杯
Take my trophy!
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance!
我死定了
I'm gonna die.
小心
Look out!
我成功了
I did it!
你们好吗
How you doing?
别担心  有我呢
Don't worry about it. I got you.
太好了
Yes! Yes!
大块头  别乱动了
Big guy, quit moving around.
抱歉  先生  真抱歉
I'm sorry, sir. So sorry.
快走
Let's go, let's go!
好了
Okay, okay.
-哈林顿老师  来  -内德  来啊
- Mr. Harrington, go. - Ned, come on.
-好了  你们到了  -来吧  丽兹
- All right. This is your stop. - Come on, Liz.
快走  都出去
Go, go, go. Everybody out!
快走啊  快走
Move it, people. Move it, move it!
-你确定安全吗  -丽兹
- Are you sure it's safe? - Liz!
你没事  你没事
You're okay. You're okay.
好了
Okay.
-天呐  -很好
- Oh, my god. - Good, good.
来吧  各位  退后
Come on up. Come on, you guys, stay back.
-进来  -没事吧
- Come on in. - You guys good?
大家都没事了吧
So is everyone okay?
你的机会来了  彼得
This is your chance, Peter.
吻她吧
Kiss her.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真跟彼得·帕克是朋友吗
Are you really friends with Peter Parker?
我可以完成下一单
I can finish the next order,
但没有车上的新材料
but without any new materials from that truck...
是啊  该死
Yeah, damn it.
我们还有足够物料完成盖根的订单吧
We still have enough to do the Gargan deal though, right?
嗯  然后就没了
Yeah, but then that's it.
或许我该做高空密封装置了
Maybe it is time that I built the high-altitude seal.
-你能不能别再念叨了  -就那一票
- Would you shut up about that? - It's only one job.
不行
No.
八年了  条子毫无动静
Eight years, not a word from the feds,
斯塔克塔上那些穿万圣节服装的白痴
nothing from those Halloween-costume-wearing bozos
也没来找过事
up there in Stark tower.
然后突然
And then all of a sudden,
冒出这么个穿红紧身衣的小混蛋
this little bastard in red tights shows up
就以为自己能毁掉我所建立的一切
and he thinks he can tear down everything I've built.
是吗
Really?
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
-我要找到他  -找到了
- I'm gonna find him-- - I found him.
蜘蛛侠从天而降  英勇地救下了
Spider-man swooped in, heroically saving
一支来自皇后区的学术竞赛队
an academic decathlon team from Queens.
这位蒙面英雄的身份仍不清楚
The identity of the masked hero is still unknown.
-妈妈  -好了  没事
- Mom. - Okay. All right.
彼得  过来
Peter? Come here, come here.
天呐
Oh, my god.
这周末  中城高中学术竞赛队
This past weekend, Midtown's academic decathlon team
击败了国内翘楚
defeated the country's best
赢下了全国冠军
to win the national championship.
当天晚些时候  他们还战胜了死神
Later that day, they also defeated death.
爆炸  莎莉叫  弗拉士叫  大家都叫
Explosion. Sally scream. Flash scream. Everybody scream.
到处是紫激光  还有烟
There were purple lasers and smoke everywhere.
太...紧张  就像邦·乔维演唱会
It was... tight, like a Bon Jovi concert.
大家知道  我们活下来了
As you know, we made it out alive,
这才是最重要的
and that's the important thing.
我可受不了在学校出行期间有学生出事
I couldn't bear to lose a student on a school trip.
不能再来一次了
Not again.
幸好  没人受重伤
Thankfully, no one was seriously injured,
这要多谢蜘蛛侠
thanks to the Spider-man.
-谢谢你  蜘蛛侠  -谢谢你  蜘蛛侠
- Thank you, Spider-man. - Thank you, Spider-man.
接下来  蜘蛛侠热横扫全校
Up next: The Spider-man mania is sweeping the school.
你要如何展现你的蜘蛛精神
How can you show your spider spirit?
哥们
Dude, dude, dude, dude, dude.
这么出名可大家又都不知道是你  是个什么感觉
What is it like being famous when nobody knows it's you?
-好疯狂  哥们  -真疯狂
- Crazy, dude. - It's crazy.
-我们要不要告诉大家  -不行
- Should we tell everyone? - No.
我要不要告诉大家
Should I tell everyone?
不行  哥们  那可不好
No, dude. That's not a good idea.
好吧  走  我们上课要迟了
Okay, come on, we'll be late to class.
我不去上课了
I'm not going to class.
你在竞赛时抛弃了我们  已经闯大祸了
You're already in so much trouble for ditching us at the decathlon.
哥们  听着  我想明白了
Dude, listen, I figured it out.
翅膀男在偷损害控制的东西
The wingsuit guy is stealing from Damage Control.
他把从损害控制偷的东西
What he takes from Damage Control,
做成武器
that's how he builds the weapons.
我只需要抓到他
So all I gotta do is catch him.
但我们还有西班牙语测试呢
But we have a Spanish quiz.
内德  我可能再也不回来了
Ned, I'm probably never gonna come back here.
斯塔克先生要把复仇者迁到州北
Mr. Stark is moving the Avengers upstate
-等我抓到这人  -哥们
- so when I bring this guy in-- - Dude.
你想高中辍学吗
You want to be a high school dropout?
高中现在根本罩不住我了
I am so far beyond high school right now.
帕克  去我办公室
Parker, my office.
好吧
So...
你被留堂了
You got detention.
你搞砸了  你知道你做错了
You screwed up. You know what you did was wrong.
问题是  你要如何弥补
The question is, how are you gonna make things right?
或许你是想扮酷
Maybe you were trying to be cool.
但听我一个冻了65年的人一句劝
But take it from a guy who's been frozen for 65 years,
真正想酷  就只能遵守规矩
the only way to really be cool is to follow the rules.
我们都分得清对错
We all know what's right. We all know what's wrong.
下次再有人
Next time those turkeys try to
想在你面前颠倒黑白
convince you of something you know is wrong...
-你去哪  回来  -就想想
- Where you going? Get back here. - Just think to yourself,
美国队长会怎么做
what would Captain America do?
你干吗坐这儿  你根本没被留堂
Why are you here? You don't even have detention.
我知道
I know.
我就是喜欢来这儿  画处于危机中的人
I just like coming here to sketch people in crisis.
是你
It's you.
你的身体在发生变化
So your body's changing.
相信我  我了解那感受
Believe me, I know how that feels.
梅
May?
凯伦  好啊
Karen. What's up?
彼得  你的西班牙语考得怎样
Peter. How was your Spanish quiz?
那个  能帮我个忙吗
Listen, I was wondering if you could help me.
我想查明那晚
I'm trying to figure out who the guys
桥下的人的身份
under the bridge were that night,
但我只能记住部分的车牌号
but I mean, I can only kinda remember part of a license plate.
我可以用当晚的视频进行面部识别
I can run facial recognition on the footage of that encounter.
-视频  -是的  彼得
- Footage? - Yes, Peter.
我会记录你看到的一切
I record everything you see.
-一切  -是的
- Everything? - Everything.
随时随地吗
Like, all the time?
这是宝贝监控协议
It's called the Baby-monitor Protocol.
当然了
Yeah, of course it is.
嗯  倒回上周五
Yeah, just roll it back to last Friday.
好的
With pleasure.
大家好  派对真棒
Everyone. Yeah, kick-ass party.
好啊  丽兹  彼得跟我说过你不少事
What's up, Liz? Peter's told me a lot about you.
不不  这是我胡闹呢
No, no, no. This is just me messing around.
快进到当天后面
Go later in the day, later in the day.
是我  托尔  奥丁之子
It is I, Thor, son of Odin!
不不
No, no, no.
那绝不是我们要看的
That's definitely-- that's not what we wanted to watch.
你的模仿非常逗
Your impressions are very funny.
快进到军火交易那里
Fast-forward to the arms deal.
好吧
Okay.
右边的俩人  是谁
The two on the right, who are they?
搜索执法部门数据库
Searching law enforcement databases.
并未找到这两人的记录
No records found for two of the individuals.
-没有吗  -一人身份确认
- Nothing? - One individual identified.
艾伦·戴维斯  33岁
Aaron Davis, age 33.
他有犯罪记录  而且就住在皇后区
He has a criminal record and an address here in Queens.
我们去会会他吧
Let's pay him a visit.
要我启动
Would you like me to activate
强化审讯模式吗
the enhanced interrogation protocol?
好啊
Yeah.
记得我吗
Remember me?
我需要情报  你得马上给我
I need information. You're gonna give it to me now.
-好吧  冷静  -快说
- All right, chill. - Come on!
你声音怎么了
What happened to your voice?
什么怎么了
What do you mean what happened to my voice?
我在桥下听到你说话了
I heard you by the bridge.
我认得出那是姑娘的声音
I know what a girl sound like.
我不是女的  我是男孩
I'm not a girl! I'm a boy.
男人...我是男人
I mean, I'm a-- I'm a man.
我才不管你是男的还是女的
I don't care what you are, a boy, a girl--
我不是女的  我是男人
I'm not a girl! I'm a man.
拜托
Come on, man.
是谁在出售武器
Look, who is selling these weapons?
我需要知道  告诉我名字  否则我不客气
I need to know. Give me names or else.
你没干过这个吧
You ain't ever done this before, huh?
关闭审讯模式
Deactivate interrogation mode.
听着  伙计
Look, man,
这些人在售卖非常危险的武器
these guys are selling weapons that are crazy dangerous.
不能任它们流入街头
They can't be out on the streets.
要是有能一下切开达尔摩小店的武器
If one of them can cut Delmar's bodega in half--
你还知道达尔摩的店
you know delmar's?
当然  皇后区最好的三明治
Yeah, best sandwich in Queens.
-三明治港也不错  -面包太厚
- Sub Haven's pretty good. - It's too much bread.
-我就喜欢面包  -拜托了  伙计
- I like bread. - Come on, man, please.
破审讯模式  凯伦  再也别启用了
Stupid interrogation mode. Karen, don't ever do that again.
那天晚上  你跟那人说
The other night, you told that dude,
"你想开枪  就冲我来吧"
"If you shoot somebody, shoot me."
挺有种的
It's pretty ballsy.
我不希望那种武器进入这一带
I don't want those weapons in this neighborhood.
我有个侄子住这儿呢
I got a nephew who live here.
那些人是谁
Who are these guys?
你能跟我讲讲那个长翅膀的男人吗
What can you tell me about the guy with the wings?
只知道他是个扮成恶魔的疯子
Other than he's a psychopath dressed like a demon, nothing.
我不知道他是谁  他在哪
I don't know who he is or where he is.
但我知道他会去哪
I do know where he's gonna be.
是吗
Really?
对  我以前合作过的一个疯子
Yeah, this crazy dude I used to work with,
他要跟那人做笔交易
he's supposed to be doing a deal with him.
太好了
Yes! Yes.
谢了
Thank--
我还没告诉你在哪呢  你都不知道地点
I didn't tell you where. You don't have a location.
是啊  抱歉  我的错  真傻
Right, of course. Yeah, my bad. Silly. Just--
好
yeah.
-在哪  -我能提点建议吗
- Where is it? - Can I give you some advice?
你这部分的能力得加强
You got to get better at this part of the job.
我不懂
I don't understand.
我很吓人的
I'm intimidating.
-斯塔顿岛渡轮  11点  -那快了
- Staten Island ferry, 11. - Oh, that's soon.
那个两小时后就能溶解
That's gonna dissolve in two hours.
不不  过来给我解开
No, no, no, no. Come fix this.
两小时  你罪有应得
Two hours. You deserve that.
-我买了冰淇淋呢  -这是罪有应得
- I got ice cream in here. - You deserve that.
你是罪犯  再见了  罪犯先生
You're a criminal. Bye, Mr. Criminal.
漂亮
Nice.
好  凯伦  启动强化侦查模式
Okay, Karen, activate enhanced reconnaissance mode.
好的
Sure thing.
他在前面  主甲板
He's up front, main deck.
我恨这家伙
I hate this guy.
这是桥下那人吧
It's the guy from the bridge, right?
-另一个是谁  -有情况通知我
- Who's that other guy? - Just keep me posted.
我在犯罪数据库里找不到他
There's no record of him in my criminal database.
梅·帕克来电
Incoming call from May Parker.
要接到你的显示器上吗
Should I reroute to your heads-up display?
我现在没法接  我回头打回去
I can't talk right now. I'll call her back.
小蛛  去盯着那家伙
Dronie, keep an eye on that guy.
这次不能让任何人逃脱
We can't let anybody get away this time.
-左边那人是谁  -麦克·盖根
- Who's the guy on the left? - Mac Gargan.
有大量案底  包括凶杀
Extensive criminal record, including homicide.
要我启动击杀功能吗
Would you like me to activate instant kill?
不  凯伦  别再提击杀功能了
No, Karen, stop it with the instant kill already.
白色皮卡
White pickup truck.
小蛛  在渡轮上搜寻白色皮卡
Dronie, scan the ship for a white pickup truck.
这也太完美了
This is too perfect.
武器  买家  卖家  一网打尽
They got the weapons, buyers and sellers in one place.
-托尼·斯塔克来电  -不不不
- Incoming call from Tony Stark. - No, no, no.
-别接  -帕克先生  有时间吗
- Don't answer. - Mr. Parker. Got a sec?
-我在上学  -你没有
- I'm actually at school. - No, you're not.
-在华盛顿特区干得漂亮  -好
- Nice work in D.C. - Okay.
我爸爸从来都没怎么支持过我
My dad never really gave me a lot of support
我想打破这个坏循环
and I'm trying to break the cycle of shame.
我现在正在忙
I'm kind of in the middle of something right now.
我夸你的时候别打断我
Don't cut me off when I'm complimenting you.
总之  大事将要...那是什么声音
Anyway, great things are about to-- what is that?
我在乐队排练
I'm at band practice.
怪了  哈皮告诉我你六周前退出乐队了
That's odd. Happy told me you quit band six weeks ago.
-怎么回事  -我得挂了  结束通话
- What's up? - I gotta go! End call.
给我吧
I'll take those!
各位  非法武器交易的那班渡轮是10点半
Hey, guys. The illegal weapons-deal ferry was at 10:30.
你们错过了
You missed it!
蜘蛛人来了
Spider guy's here.
想得美
Not so fast.
你们没事吧  我错了  下手有点重了
Are you guys okay? My bad. That was a little hard.
我得说  另一个人比你用得好多了
I got to say, the other guy was way better with that thing.
我真是
I'm honestly--
被惊住了
I'm-- I'm shocked.
-不许动  联调局  -不许动
- Freeze! FBI! - Don't move!
-趴在地上  -联调局
- Get on the ground! - FBI!
等等  联调局  什么意思
Wait. What do you mean, FBI?
联调局全称联邦调查局
The FBI is the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
我知道联调局是什么  但他们来这儿干吗
I know what "FBI" means. But what are they doing here?
搞什么
What the--?
让开  让开
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
快走
Go, go, go, go!
快闪开
Get out of there!
小心  快走  快走
Look out! Look out! Look out! Move! Move! Move!
-快走  -去顶层甲板
- Move! - Get to the top deck.
我们走
We're getting out of here.
启动电击蛛网
Activate taser web!
你这是在摆弄你不了解的东西
You're messing with things you don't understand.
天啊  我怎么办
Oh, my god. What do I do?
凯伦  X光扫描这艘船
Karen, give me an X-ray of the boat
标出所有最坚固的点
and target all the strongest points.
蛛网手雷  蛛网手雷
Web grenade. Web grenade.
分流蛛网  出
Splitter web, go.
干得好  彼得  你成功了98%
Great job, Peter. You are 98 percent successful.
-98%  -棒啊  蜘蛛侠
- Ninety-eight? - Yeah, Spider-Man!
不不不
No, no, no.
不
No!
怎么会
What the hell?
怎么回事
好啊  蜘蛛侠
Hi, Spider-Man.
乐队排练是吧
Band practice, was it?
看  看
Look! Look!
棒啊  钢铁侠
Yeah, Iron Man!
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
斯塔克先生  我能做什么吗
Mr. Stark, could I do anything?
你要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
你做得够多了
I think you've done enough.
就这样了  你要逃跑了
So that's it? You're just gonna run?
联调局埋伏在那里
Feds were waiting for us.
现在我们又被钢铁侠盯上了
Now we're on Iron Man's radar?
对  我是要逃跑
Yeah, I'm running.
你也该跑
You should too.
你知道我不能
You know I can't do that.
那现在怎么办
So now what?
梅森
Mason,
你能及时做好那个高空密封装置吗
can you get that high-altitude seal thing up and running in time?
真的吗
Seriously?
能  你不会后悔的
Yes. You will not regret this.
你加入吗
You in?
《彼得闯大祸》前情提要
Previously on Peter Screws the Pooch,
我叫你别管这事
I tell you to stay away from this.
但你黑进了价值几百万的战衣
Instead, you hacked a multimillion-dollar suit
好偷偷背着我
so you could sneak around behind my back
做我不让你做的事
doing the one thing I told you not to do.
大家都没事吧
Is everyone okay?
反正你没帮上忙
No thanks to you.
我没帮上忙
No thanks to me?
那些武器流通在外  我一直想尽办法告诉你
Those weapons were out there and I tried to tell you about it,
但你不听
but you didn't listen.
要是你肯听我的  这些事都不会发生
None of this would've happened if you had just listened to me.
你要是你真在乎的话  就会亲自来了
If you even cared, you'd actually be here.
我听了  孩子
I did listen, kid.
你以为是谁把联调局叫来的
Who do you think called the FBI, huh?
你知道我是唯一一个相信你的人吗
Do you know I was the only one who believed in you?
其他人都说我疯了
Everyone else said I was crazy
-招来个14岁的小孩  -我15
- to recruit a 14-year-old kid. - I'm 15.
不  你把嘴闭严了  好吗
No. This is where you zip it, all right?
大人说话别插嘴
The adult is talking.
要是今晚有人死了怎么办
What if somebody had died tonight?
那可就不一样了  对吧  那是你的责任
Different story, right? 'Cause that's on you.
要是你死了
And if you died,
我会觉得责任在我
I feel like that's on me.
我可不想良心不安
I don't need that on my conscience.
-是啊  先生  我很抱歉  -是啊
- Yes, sir, I'm sorry. - Yes.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-对不起也没用  -我明白
- Sorry doesn't cut it. - I understand.
我只是想像你一样
I just wanted to be like you.
但我希望你比我强
And I wanted you to be better.
好吧  这样不行
Okay, it's not working out.
我得收回战衣
I'm gonna need the suit back.
-收回多久  -永久收回
- For how long? - Forever.
-对  就是这样  -不  不  拜托
- Yeah, that's how it works. - No, no. Please. Please.
-快脱吧  -你不明白
- Let's have it. - You don't understand.
这是我的一切  没有这套战衣我一无是处
This is all I have. I'm nothing without this suit.
如果没有这套战衣你就一无是处
If you're nothing without this suit,
那你就不配拥有它  好吗
then you shouldn't have it, okay?
天哪  我口气跟我爸一样
God, I sound like my dad.
我没别的衣服了
I don't have any other clothes.
好吧  我们会想办法的
Okay, we'll sort that out.
我给你打了一天电话
I've been calling you all day.
你一直不接
You didn't answer your phone.
你不能这样做
You can't do that.
然后渡轮出了事
Then this ferry thing happens.
我打电话问了五个警局
I've called five police stations.
五个  我还给你五个朋友打了电话
Five. I called five of your friends.
-我给内德的妈妈打了电话  -我没事
- I called Ned's mother. - I'm fine.
梅  我没事
May, I'm okay.
真的  放松  我没事
Honestly, just relax. I'm fine.
别胡扯了  我知道你逃了留校
Cut the bullshit. I know you left detention.
我知道你离开了华盛顿的酒店房间
I know you left the hotel room in Washington.
我知道你每天晚上都从家偷溜出去
I know you sneak out of this house every night.
这可不行
That's not fine.
彼得  你得告诉我到底怎么了
Peter, you have to tell me what's going on.
说出来吧  这里只有我们两个
Just lay it out. It's just me and you.
我丢了在斯塔克的实习工作
I lost the Stark internship.
-什么  -是的
- What? - Yeah.
出什么事了
What happened?
我只是以为我可以努力工作
I just thought that I could work really hard
然后他就会...就会...
and he could-- he would-- you know.
但是...我搞砸了
But...I screwed it up.
没事的  没事的
Oh, it's okay, it's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
抱歉我让你担心了
I'm sorry I made you worry.
你明白我并不是想毁掉你的生活
You know I'm not trying to ruin your life.
我明白
Yeah, I know.
只是...
Just--
-我以前也会偷溜出去  -嗯
- I used to sneak out too. - Yeah.
洗个澡吧  你臭死了
And take a shower. You smell.
你身上一股...垃圾味儿
You smell like-- you smell like garbage.
我知道
I know.
彼得  你是个好孩子  聪明的孩子
Peter, you're a good kid and you're a smart kid,
所以  把精神用在正地方  好吗
so just try to keep your head straight, okay?
好
Okay.
好了  出去吧
All right, get out of here.
你是不是被开除了
Are you expelled?
你是不是要去46街那个高中
Do you have to go to that school on 46th
他们校长有把十字弩
where their principal has a crossbow?
那八成只是街头传闻
Pretty sure that's an urban myth,
不  我没有被开除
and, no, I'm not expelled.
你真走运
You're so lucky.
很好  帕克先生
Muy bueno, senor Parker.
我以为你第五节课要上微积分
I thought you had calculus fifth period.
是啊  我只是在做返校节的东西
Yeah, I was just doing some homecoming stuff.
我...
Hey, look, I--
我想为学术竞赛的事道歉
I just wanted to apologize about the whole decathlon thing.
-没关系  -真抱歉
- It's fine. - Really.
上周  学术竞赛是最重要的事
Last week, decathlon was the most important thing,
但接着  我死里逃生
but then I almost died.
不  我只是...
No, I just-- I'm--
我只是说
I just mean that
那样很不好  尤其...
it was not cool, especially...
因为...
Because...
我喜欢你
I like you.
我知道
I know.
你知道
You do?
你太不会保密了
You're terrible at keeping secrets.
这你就不知道了
Yeah, you'd be surprised.
我得去上课了  但是...
I got to get to class, but--
我想说我们应该一起聊聊
I'd say we should hang out,
但是我还要留校...
but I'm gonna be in detention for...
留很久  但是...
Ever, but--
我猜你已经有返校节舞会舞伴了
I guess you already have a date to homecoming.
其实  我一直在忙着准备
Actually, I was so busy planning it,
还没来得及找  所以...
I never really got around to that part, so...
你愿意
You want to
做我的舞伴吗
go with me?
当然愿意
Yeah. Sure.
真的吗  太好了
Really? I mean, great. Cool.
好
Cool.
我应该往那边走
I'm actually going that way.
BGM: Save It For Later  By  The Beat
梅  我需要你的帮助
May, I need your help.
对吧
Right?
大日子到了  说说计划
It's game day. So what's the plan?
给她开门
Open the door for her.
夸她漂亮  但别太过了
Tell her she looks nice, but not too much
-不然会吓到人家  -别吓到人家
- because that's creepy. - Don't be creepy.
好  跟她跳舞的时候
No. And when I dance with her,
把手放在她的胯上  我行的
I'm putting my hands on her hips. I got this.
-爱你  -再见
- Love you. - Bye.
你一定就是彼得了
You must be Peter.
是的
Yeah.
我是丽兹的爸爸
I'm Liz's dad.
握个手吧
Put 'er there.
手挺有劲儿
Hell of a grip.
进来吧  来
Come on in here. Come on.
你好  彼得
Hi, Peter.
挺帅嘛
You look very handsome.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没叫错他的名字吧
You got his name right?
-弗雷迪吗  -是彼得
- Freddie? - Peter.
彼得  彼得
Peter. Peter.
我去叫丽兹
I'm gonna go get Liz.
好
Okay.
你没事吧  彼得
You all right, Pete?
嗯
Yeah.
因为你脸色很苍白
Because you look pale.
想来点喝的吗
You want something to drink?
波本
Like a bourbon
或者威士忌之类的
or a scotch, or something like that?
我还没到能喝酒的年龄
I'm not old enough to drink.
回答正确
That's the right answer.
你可真美
Do you look beautiful.
别丢人了  爸爸
Please don't embarrass me, dad.
是吧  彼得
Doesn't she, Pete?
是啊  你真的很美
Yeah, you look really good.
又是正确答案
Once again, that's the right answer.
那是胸花吗
Is that a corsage?
谢谢
Thanks.
我是你们的司机
Well, hey, I'm your chauffeur,
我们赶紧上路吧
so let's get this show on the road.
不不不  我们得先拍几张照片  宝贝
No, no, no, we have to take some pictures, babe.
好了
All right.
-这儿呢  完美  -妈妈
- Oh, right here. Perfect. - Mom.
好了  你们俩过来
Okay. Come on, you guys.
彼得  靠近点
Peter, closer.
笑一笑
Smile.
好了
There you go.
先生  你不用开车送我们的
Sir, you don't have to drive us.
不不  小事一桩
Nah, nah, it's not a big deal.
我正要出城  顺路
I'm going out of town. It's right on my way.
他老是出门忙活
He's always coming and going.
-最后一次了  -好好玩
- Last time. - Have fun.
-谢谢你  -我保证
- Thank you. - Promise.
他很可爱
He's cute.
几天后见
See you in a couple of days.
-再见  宝贝  -好
- Bye, baby. - All right.
走吧  小彼
Come on, Pedro.
-再见  彼得  好好玩  -我会的
- Bye, Peter. Have fun. - Yeah, I will.
你打算做什么  彼得
What are you gonna do, Pete?
什么
What?
你毕业后  你打算做什么
When you graduate, what do you think you'll do?
-我不知道  -别拷问他  爸爸
- Oh, I don't know. - Don't grill him, dad.
我就问问
Just saying, you know.
你们上那么好的学校
All you guys who go to that school
应该都已经规划好自己的人生了吧
you pretty much have your life planned out, right?
没有  我还在读高二
Yeah, no, I'm just a sophomore.
彼得在托尼·斯塔克的公司实习
Peter has an internship with Tony Stark.
所以我觉得他不用担心
So I think he doesn't have to worry.
真的吗
Really?
-斯塔克  -多棒
- Stark? - So cool.
你是做什么的
What do you do?
其实我已经不在他那里实习了
Actually, I don't intern for him anymore.
-真的吗  -是啊  有点...
- Seriously? - Yeah, it got...
无聊了
Boring.
无聊吗
It was boring?
你还有机会见蜘蛛侠呢
You got to hang out with spider-man.
真的吗  蜘蛛侠
Really? Spider-man?
他是怎样的人
What's he like?
他挺好
Yeah, he's nice.
人挺好
Nice man.
很可靠
Solid dude.
看  多可爱啊
Look. So cute.
我在哪里见过你吧
I've seen you around, right?
在什么地方
I mean, somewhere.
我们有没有...因为你的声音也...
We've-- have we ever--? Because even the voice--
他和我一起参加了学术竞赛
He does academic decathlon with me.
他还来过我的派对
And he was at my party.
派对很棒
It was a great party.
真的很棒
Really great, yeah.
房子真漂亮  有很多窗户
Beautiful house, a lot of windows.
你才待了一小会儿
You were there for, like, two seconds.
那是...
That was--
也没那么短吧
I was there longer than two seconds.
-你消失了  -没有
- You disappeared. - No.
-不  我没有消失  -你消失了
- No, I did not disappear. - Yes, you did.
你和往常一样消失了
You disappeared like you always do.
你在华盛顿也是
Like you did in D.C. too.
华盛顿发生的事太可怕了
That's terrible what happened down there in D.C. though.
你害怕吗
Were you scared?
你看到你的老朋友蜘蛛侠
I'll bet you were glad when your old pal spider-man
出现在电梯里时肯定很高兴吧
showed up in the elevator though, huh?
其实当时我没有上去
Yeah, well, I actually didn't go up.
我是在地面上看到的
I saw it all from the ground.
嗯
Yeah.
还好他那天在
Very lucky that he was there that day.
好伙计蜘蛛侠
Good old spider-man.
爸爸  绿灯了
Dad, the light.
我们到了  到地方了
Here we are. End of the line.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, dad.
你先进去吧  宝贝
You head in there, gumdrop.
我要给彼得来一场"父亲训话"
I'm gonna give Peter the "Dad" talk.
别被他吓到了
Don't let him intimidate you.
爱你
Love you.
-爱你  宝贝  -一路顺风
- Love you, gumdrop. - Have a safe flight.
你们看上去真美
You guys look so pretty.
她知道吗
Does she know?
知道什么
Know what?
那么她不知道  很好
So she doesn't. Good.
会保守秘密  这点我很钦佩
Close to the vest. I admire that.
我自己也有一些秘密
I've got a few secrets of my own.
我有那么多理由反对我女儿约会  到头来...
Of all the reasons i didn't want my daughter to date...
彼得
Peter,
没有什么比家庭更重要
nothing is more important than family.
你救了我女儿的命
You saved my daughter's life.
我绝不会忘记这种恩情
I could never forget something like that.
所以我给你一个机会
So I'm gonna give you one chance.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
你走进去
You walk through those doors,
忘掉这些事
you forget any of this happened
永远不准
and don't you ever,
再来
ever
插手我的生意
interfere with my business again.
否则
'Cause if you do,
我会杀了你
I'll kill you
和你爱的每个人
and everybody you love.
我会要你的命
I'll kill you dead.
这是我为了保护家人能做出的事  彼得
That's what I'll do to protect my family, Pete.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
我刚刚救了你的命  你该怎么说
I just saved your life. Now what do you say?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
你现在进去
Now, you go on in there,
让我女儿好好开心一下  知道了吗
you show my daughter a good time, okay?
也别太开心了
Just not too good.
他和你说了什么
What did he say to you?
我得走了
I've got to go.
对不起
I'm-- I'm sorry.
这对你不公平
You don't deserve this.
他给了你选择
He gave you a choice.
-你选错了  -搞什么
- You chose wrong. - What the hell?
这破烂衣服是怎么回事
What's with the crappy costume?
我的射网器
My web-shooters.
我本来还对这玩意抱有怀疑  但是...
I wasn't sure about this thing at first, but...
天啊
Damn.
真恶心
Gross.
-他为什么派你来  -你永远不会知道了
- Why did he send you here? - Guess you'll never know.
漂亮
Nice shot!
太好了
Yes!
内德  那个有翅膀的家伙是丽兹的爸爸
Ned, the guy with the wings is Liz's dad.
-什么  -我知道  我得告诉斯塔克先生
- What? - I know. I gotta tell Mr. Stark.
联系哈皮·霍根  他是斯塔克先生的安保主管
Call Happy Hogan. He's Mr. Stark's head of security.
去找一台电脑  帮我追踪我的手机
And get a computer and track my phone for me.
你没事吧
Are you gonna be okay?
快点  我们得在他出城前抓住他
Hurry, we gotta catch him before he leaves town.
晚餐的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about dinner, but
但我知道新鲜柠檬鲈鱼什么味儿
I know when branzino's fresh,
那绝对不新鲜  好吗
and that was not fresh, okay?
所以...
So--
弗拉士  我需要你的车和你的手机
Flash, I need your car and your phone.
先生  严格来说这是我爸的车
Sir, technically, this is my dad's car, sir,
所以我不能
so I can't--
内德  你听得到吗
Hello, Ned? Hey, hey, can you hear me?
这里是内德
Go for Ned.
内德  我需要你帮我追踪我的手机
Ned, I need you to track my phone for me.
好  但你的手机在哪
Yeah, but where is it?
太聪明了  他刚刚经过杰克逊大道的游戏站
Genius move. Okay, he just passed the gamestop on Jackson Avenue.
这玩意的前灯怎么开
Where are the headlights on this thing?
-我在开弗拉士的车  -我来查操作说明书
- I'm in Flash's car. - I'll pull the specs.
好的  给你开免提了
Okay, you're on speakerphone.
你偷了弗拉士的车  赞
You stole Flash's car? Awesome.
是啊  很赞  很...
Yeah, it's awesome! It's awe--
让开  让开  快点  快点
Get out of the way! Get out of the way! Move! Move!
-彼得  你没事吧  -我从来没开过车
- Peter, are you okay? - I've never driven before.
就和梅在停车场练过
Only with May in parking lots.
这跨度也太大了
This is a huge step up.
你联系到哈皮了吗
Have you gotten through to Happy yet?
嗯  我正在努力
Yeah. I'm working on it.
我得攻破手机系统的后门
I just gotta backdoor the phone system.
技术支援
Guy in the chair.
九分钟后起飞
Takeoff in nine minutes.
喂  喂  谁啊
Hello? Hello? Who is this?
-哈皮先生  我是内德  -谁
- Mr. Happy, it's Ned. - Who?
我是彼得·帕克的同伴
I'm an associate of Peter Parker.
有很重要的事要和你说...
Got something important to tell you--
你在逗我吧
You gotta be shitting me.
该死
Damn.
内德  搞清楚前灯怎么用了吗
Ned, how we coming with those headlights?
方向盘左边的圆形把手
Round knob to the left of the steering wheel,
-顺时针转  -左边  好了
- turn clockwise. - Left, okay.
完美  我的手机现在在哪里
Okay, perfect. So where's my phone now?
他停在了布鲁克林一家旧工业园区
He stopped in an old industrial park in Brooklyn.
什么  那没道理啊
What? That makes no sense!
我以为他说他要出城了
I thought he said he was going out of town!
真奇怪  我联系到了哈皮先生
Weird. Oh, I reached Mr. Happy.
他好像不是很喜欢你
Don't think he likes you, by the way.
他好像正忙着赶飞机
Sounded like he was catching a flight.
说什么九分钟后起飞
He said something about taking off in nine minutes.
-什么  -他边上都是箱子
- What? - He was surrounded by boxes.
箱子  今天是搬家日
Boxes? It's moving day.
是搬家日  搬家日  他要劫那架飞机
It's moving day. It's moving day. He's gonna rob that plane.
我得阻止他
I gotta stop him!
好了  八分钟后起飞
All right, wheels up in eight minutes.
只要再装上托尼的旧反浩克盔甲
We just got to load Tony's old hulkbuster armor,
队长新盾牌的原型机  还有梅金...
prototype for Cap's new shield, and the meging--
梅金...
the Meg-- the--
托尔的魔法腰带
Thor's magic belt.
慢点  你接近了
Okay, slow down. You're getting close.
-就在你右边  -什么
- It's on your right. - What?
右转  右转
Turn right! Turn right!
-彼得  你没事吧  -没事
- Peter, are you okay? - Yeah.
继续尝试联系哈皮
Just keep trying to get through to Happy.
很荣幸  蜘蛛侠
It's been an honor, Spider-Man.
你在干什么  在举办舞会呢
What are you doing here? There's a dance.
我在看...
I'm looking...
黄片
at porn.
没想到吧
Surprised?
彼得
Pete.
我没听见你进来
I didn't hear you come in.
都结束了  我抓住你了
It's over. I've got you.
我得说  彼得
You know, I gotta tell you, Pete,
我真的  真的佩服你的勇气
I really, really admire your grit.
我能看出丽兹为什么喜欢你
I see why Liz likes you.
真的  你刚走进我家门时
I do. When you first came to the house,
我还不确定  我想"就这小子吗"
I wasn't sure. I thought, "Really?"
但我现在明白了
But I get it now.
你怎么能这样对她
How could you do this to her?
对她  我没有对她做任何事  彼得
To her? I'm not doing anything to her, Pete.
我做这些都是为了她
I'm doing this for her.
是啊
Yeah.
彼得
Peter,
你很年轻
you're young.
你不明白这个世界是怎么样的
You don't understand how the world works.
但我明白
Yeah, but I understand
把武器卖给罪犯是错的
that selling weapons to criminals is wrong.
你以为你的朋友斯塔克哪来的钱造那幢大楼
How do you think your buddy Stark paid for that tower?
还有他那些小玩具
Or any of his little toys?
那些人  彼得
Those people, Pete,
那些高高在上  有权有势的人
those people up there, the rich and the powerful,
可以为所欲为
they do whatever they want.
我们这样的人  像你和我
Guys like us, like you and me,
他们根本就不会在乎
they don't care about us.
我们为他们铺设道路  为他们浴血作战什么的
We build their roads and we fight all their wars and everything,
但他们根本不在乎我们
but they don't care about us.
我们得跟在他们后头捡漏
We have to pick up after 'em.
我们只能吃他们的残羹冷炙
We have to eat their table scraps.
这世界就是这样
That's how it is.
我知道你明白我在说什么  彼得
I know you know what I'm talking about, Peter.
你为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
因为我希望你能理解
Because I want you to understand.
而且
And...
它需要一点时间才能起飞
I needed a little time to get her airborne.
对不起  彼得
I'm sorry, Peter.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
那东西根本就没刮到我
That thing hasn't even touched me yet.
没错  但是
True. Then again,
根本没打算刮到你
wasn't really trying to.
老大  他们发动引擎了
Chief, they're powering up engines.
-好的  知道了  -快点  快点
- Okay. Yeah, yeah. - Come on, come on, come on.
天啊
God.
准备
Okay, ready?
有人吗
Hello!
救命啊
Please.
救命啊  我在下面
Please. I'm down here.
我在下面  我被卡住了
I'm down here. I'm stuck.
我卡住了  我动不了  我动...
I'm stuck. I can't move. I can't--
如果没有这套战衣你就一无是处
If you're nothing without this suit,
那你就不配拥有它
then you shouldn't have it.
加油  彼得
Come on, Peter.
加油  蜘蛛侠
Come on, Spider-Man.
出发拦截  行动  行动
Launch for intercept. Green light. Green light.
好啊
Oh, yeah.
启动反光板
Retroreflective panels engaged.
看到飞机了
Got a visual on the plane,
但我感觉好像有点阻力
but I'm feeling a little resistance.
可能只是新涡轮的曳力
It's probably just drag on the new turbines.
小心隐形摄像机
Look out for the cloaking cameras.
躲在盲区里
Stay in the blind spots.
我的天啊  我的天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
启动高空真空密封
Deploy high-altitude vacuum seal.
最好管用  梅森
This better work, Mason.
相信我  老大  这里一个箱子
Trust me, boss, even one of those boxes
-都够我们吃一辈子  -嗯
- and we are set for life. - Yeah.
你有30秒时间进入驾驶舱
You have 30 seconds to get to the cockpit
超控他们的安保程序
and override their security.
复制应答机信号
Cloning transponder signal.
发射诱饵无人机
Launching decoy drone.
设定新坐标
Entering new coordinates.
很好  那么一切顺利
Good, so it's on its way?
是的  先生  航线正常
Yes, sir, right on course.
好  谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
好了
All right.
我的乖乖
Hot dog.
只是一个普通的返校节
Just a typical homecoming
趴在一架隐形飞机外
on the outside of an invisible jet...
对付我女朋友的爸爸
Fighting my girlfriend's dad.
天啊
Oh, God!
真不敢相信这样也行
I can't believe that worked.
老大  飞机在坠落  赶紧离开
Chief, Chief, they're losing altitude. Get out of there.
我不要空手而归
I'm not going home empty-handed.
天呐
Oh, my god.
快走  你在干什么
Get out of there. What are you doing?
转向啊  转向啊
Please turn! Please turn!
好啊  小彼
Pedro.
中奖了
Bingo.
你的翅膀战衣
Your wingsuit.
你的翅膀要炸了
Your wingsuit's gonna explode!
该回家了  彼得
Time to go home, Pete.
我是想救你
I'm trying to save you!
不
No!
No.
不
No!
看上去好疯狂  整件...
It looked so insane. That whole--
简直疯了
like, it was just crazy.
他就...
He was just, like...
你就...
And you were like, "Ah!"
然后我拿那个打中了他
And then I just hit him with the "Fffew."
简直...天呐
It was so-- oh, my god.
你救了我
You saved me.
太赞了
It was awesome.
丽兹
Liz.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
再见
Bye.
丽兹
Liz.
丽兹  我很抱歉
Liz, look, I'm so sorry.
你老说抱歉
You say that a lot.
这次又是为了什么
What are you sorry for this time?
舞会的事
The dance?
那是挺过分的
That was a pretty crappy thing to do.
是啊  但是  你爸爸
Well, yeah, but I-- I mean, your dad--
我无法想象你现在的感觉
I can't imagine what you're going through.
要是我能帮上什么
If there's anything I can do to help...
我猜我们要搬去俄勒冈州了
I guess we're moving to Oregon.
妈妈说那里挺不错的  所以还好了
Mom says it's nice there, so that's cool.
反正  爸爸不希望我们庭审期间待在这里
Anyways, dad doesn't want us here during the trial, so...
丽兹  我
Liz, I-- I--
再见  彼得
Bye, Peter.
不管你究竟有什么事
Whatever's going on with you,
我希望你能解决
I hope you figure it out.
恭喜  学术竞赛全国冠军们
Congratulations, decathlon national champions.
好啊
Yeah!
我稍后要把这个放回奖杯陈列柜里
I'm gonna have to put this back in the trophy case soon,
现在练习期间  放在这里作为激励
but just for motivation right now at this practice.
我有点超前了
I'm a little ahead of the game,
但我们明年需要位新队长
but we will need a new team captain next year.
所以我要指派米歇尔
So I am appointing Michelle.
好啊
Yeah!
谢谢
Thank you.
我的朋友喊我MJ
My-- my friends call me MJ.
你不是没有朋友吗
I thought you didn't have any friends.
现在有了
I didn't.
-我得走了  -你要去哪
- I gotta go. - Hey, where you going?
你在隐瞒什么  彼得
What are you hiding, Peter?
开玩笑的  我才不关心  去吧
I'm just kidding. I don't care. Bye.
好了  我们该排练一下
All right, so we should run some drills.
嗯
Yeah.
哈皮  你怎么在这里
Happy. What-- what are you doing here?
我真的欠你个人情
I really owe you one.
我要是没了这份工作真不知如何是好
I don't know what I would do without this job.
我认识托尼之前
I mean, before I met Tony--
你在这里待了多久了
So how long you been here?
反正是够尴尬了  老板想见你
Long enough to be awkward. Boss wants to see you.
他也在这里吗
Is he here too?
在厕所里吗  不  他在州北
In the toilet? No, he's upstate.
州北  就那个地方吗
Upstate? Like, upstate-upstate?
是啊  走吧
Yeah, let's go.
看看
Take a look.
挺气派吧
It's pretty impressive, huh?
他们刚完成整体重装
They just finished remodeling the whole thing.
这可不是每天都看得见的
You don't see that every day.
他们来了
There they are.
来得路上怎么样
How was the ride up?
挺好的
Good.
让我跟这孩子单独谈会儿
Give me a minute with the kid.
-真的吗  -是的
- Seriously? - Yeah.
我得跟孩子谈谈
I got to talk to the kid.
我就跟在后面
I'll be close behind.
跟远点吧
How about a loose follow?
行吗  距离产生美
All right? Boundaries are good.
抱歉我拿走了你的战衣
Sorry I took your suit.
虽然你是活该
I mean, you had it coming.
事实证明  这是正合适的
Actually, it turns out it was the perfect
你需要的严厉管教  是吧
sorta tough-love moment that you needed, right?
敦促你发奋  你说是吧
To urge you on? Right? Wouldn't you think?
-是吧  -嗯
- Don't you think? - Yeah.
-大概是吧  -就算是吧
- I guess. - Let's just say it was.
斯塔克先生  我...
Mr. Stark, I really--
你闯了大祸
You screwed the pooch hard, bigtime.
但之后你做了正确的事
But then you did the right thing.
你带狗狗去了免费诊所
Took the dog to the free clinic,
然后养大了混血狗崽
you raised the hybrid puppies.
好吧  这个比喻不是很好
All right, not my best analogy.
我错怪你了
I was wrong about you.
我觉得  稍加指教
I think, with a little more mentoring,
你可以成为团队里有价值的一员
you could be a real asset to the team.
-队员  -是啊
- To the-- to the team? - Yeah. Anyway,
那扇门后有50来个记者
there's about 50 reporters behind that door.
真记者  不是博主
Real ones, not bloggers.
等你准备好了
When you're ready,
试试这件吧
why don't you try that on?
我会向世界介绍
And I'll introduce the world
复仇者联盟的最新正式成员
to the newest official member of the Avengers:
蜘蛛侠
Spider-man.
我...
I--
嗯  看看吧
Yeah, give that a look.
发布会之后
So after the press conference,
哈皮会带你回房间  你的新住处
Happy will show you to your room, your new quarters.
给他安排在哪了  幻视隔壁吗
Where's he between? He's next to Vision?
嗯  幻视不怎么走门
Yeah, Vision's not big on doors.
-挺好玩的  -还穿墙
- It's fun. - Or walls.
你能很好融入的
You'll fit right in.
谢谢  斯塔克先生
Thank you, Mr. Stark,
但是  还是不用了
but I'm-- I'm good.
不用了  怎么说
You're good? How are you good?
我是说
Well, I mean,
我还是想再多脚踏实地一阵子
I'd rather just stay on the ground for a little while.
做个友善的好街坊蜘蛛侠
Friendly neighborhood Spider-man.
总得有人去照顾小人物嘛
Somebody's got to look out for the little guy, right?
你要拒绝我吗
You're turning me down?
你想清楚了  看那个啊
You better think about this. Look at that.
看我
Look at me.
最后机会  要不要
Last chance. Yes or no?
-不要  -好
- No. - Okay.
这种斯普林斯汀
It's kind of a Springsteen-y,
工人阶级英雄的气概我还蛮喜欢的
working-class hero vibe that I dig.
哈皮会送你回家
Happy will take you home.
-行吧  -好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
能去车里等着吗  我需要点时间
Mind waiting in the car? I need a minute.
谢谢  斯塔克先生
Thank you, Mr. Stark.
不客气  帕克先生  那好
Yes, Mr. Parker, very well.
-回见  -好
- See you around. - Okay.
刚刚是试我吧
That was a test, right?
那后面根本没人
There's nobody back there?
是啊  你通过了
Yes, you passed.
好了  快走吧
All right, skedaddle there,
-谢谢  斯塔克先生  谢谢  -小家伙
- Thank you, Mr. Stark. Thank you. - young buck.
谢谢你才对
Yeah, thank you.
就说他是个好孩子吧
Told you he was a good kid.
派珀  派珀
Pepper! Pepper!
那孩子呢
Where's the kid?
-他走了  -大家都等着呢
- He left. - Everybody's waiting.
其实  他做了个很成熟的决定
You know what, he actually made a really mature choice.
就是让我们措手不及
It just surprised the heck out of us.
你们搞砸了吗
Did you guys screw this up?
他叫那孩子去车里等着了
He told the kid to go wait in the car.
开什么玩笑  那一屋子的人
Are you kidding me? I have a room full of people
都在等待一个重大消息
and they're waiting for some big announcement.
我要跟他们说什么
What am I gonna tell them?
想点别的吧  比如
Think of something. How about, um,
哈皮  戒指你还带着吗
Hap, you still got that ring?
我...
Do I-- I--
-订婚戒指  -开玩笑吗
- the engagement ring. - Are you kidding?
我从2008年带到现在
I've been carrying this since 2008.
好吧
Okay.
我觉得我能想到比那个好的
I think I can think of something better than that.
这能给我们争取点时间嘛
Well, it would buy us a little time.
我们也不需要时间了
Like we need time.
真不敢相信你把那玩意就揣兜里
I can't believe you have that thing in your pocket.
要我替你开门吗  亲爱的
Let me to get the door for you, hon?
我来吧
I got it.
梅婶婶  你做晚饭了吗
Aunt May, did you do dinner already?
梅
May?
怎么回...
What the f--?!
看看这是谁
Look who it is.
多巧啊
What are the odds
咱俩进了同一个夏令营
you and I'd end up at the same summer camp?
放松
Relax.
这  不怪你
This? It's not on you.
要怪我们那位蜘蛛小朋友
It's on our little spider friend.
我在外面有人
I've got some boys on the outside
他们很想认识认识他
who would love to meet him.
拍张合照
You know, take a picture,
割了他的喉咙  把他脑袋塞进烘干机
slice his throat, put his head in a dryer.
我听到传闻说
And I heard a rumor...
你知道他的身份
You know who he is.
要是我知道
If I knew who he was,
他早就死了
he'd already be dead.
图姆斯  你的家人来了
Toomes, your family's here!
我是美国队长
I'm Captain America,
我要跟你们谈谈  一名士兵或学生能拥有的
here to talk to you about one of the most valuable traits
最宝贵的品质之一
a soldier or student can have.
耐心
Patience.
有时  耐心能换来胜利
Sometimes patience is the key to victory.
有时  却回报甚少
Sometimes it leads to very little
会让人觉得很不值
and it seems like it's not worth it.
你会想
And you wonder
当初何必等那么久
why you waited so long
盼来的却是失望
for something so disappointing.
这玩意还要拍几条
How many more of these?